<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<legal_numbering_exchange xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="M:/GDM/Projects/SAP_TARIC/Schema/TARIC_Texts.xsd">
<head>
<version>CAExp_20260101</version>
<version_date>2026-01-01</version_date>
<version_number>00007</version_number>
<upload_initial>true</upload_initial>
<schema_id>_DHSCAExp</schema_id>
<content_type>102</content_type>
<date_dependent>true</date_dependent>
<country_dependent>false</country_dependent>
<special_units_of_measure>3</special_units_of_measure>
<schema_description>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Export Codes of Canada</text>
</schema_description>
<countries>
<iso_country_code>CA</iso_country_code>
</countries>
<level>
<level_id>10</level_id>
<length>2</length>
<separator/>
<usage/>
<level_description>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Chapter</text>
</level_description>
</level>
<level>
<level_id>20</level_id>
<length>2</length>
<separator/>
<usage/>
<level_description>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Heading</text>
</level_description>
</level>
<level>
<level_id>30</level_id>
<length>2</length>
<separator/>
<usage/>
<level_description>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Sub-Heading</text>
</level_description>
</level>
<level>
<level_id>40</level_id>
<length>2</length>
<separator/>
<usage/>
<level_description>
<language>EN</language>
<text>HS Code</text>
</level_description>
</level>
</head>
<body>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN01</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN01</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Note 1. This chapter covers all live animals except: (a) Fish and crustaceans, molluscs and other aquatic invertebrates, of heading 0301, 0306, 0307 or 0308; (b) Cultures of microorganisms and other products of heading 3002; and (c) Animals of heading 9508.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN02</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN02</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Note 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Products of the kinds described in headings 0201 to 0208 or 0210, unfit or unsuitable for human consumption; (b) Guts, bladders, or stomachs of animals (heading 0504) or animal blood (heading 0511 or 3002); or (c) Animal fat, other than products of heading 0209 (chapter 15)
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN03</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN03</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Note 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Mammals of heading 0106; (b) Meat of mammals of heading 0106 (heading 0208 or 0210); (c) Fish (including livers and roes thereof) or crustaceans, molluscs or other aquatic invertebrates, dead and unfit or unsuitable for human consumption by reason of either their species or their condition (chapter 5); flours, meals or pellets of fish or of crustaceans, molluscs or other aquatic invertebrates, unfit for human consumption (heading 2301); or (d) Caviar or caviar substitutes prepared from fish eggs (heading 1604). 2. In this chapter the term "pellets" means products which have been agglomerated either directly by compression or by the addition of a small quantity of binder.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN04</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN04</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. The expression "milk" means full cream milk or partially or completely skimmed milk. 2. For the purposes of heading 0405: 	(a) The term "butter" means natural butter, whey butter or recombined butter (fresh, salted or rancid, including canned butter) 		derived exclusively from milk, with a milkfat content of 80 percent or more but not more than 95 percent by weight, a maximum 		milk solids-not-fat content of 2 percent by weight and a maximum water content of 16 percent by weight. Butter does not 		contain added emulsifiers, but may contain sodium chloride, food colors, neutralizing salts and cultures of harmless 		lactic-acid-producing bacteria. 	(b) The expression "dairy spreads" means a spreadable emulsion of the water-in-oil type, containing milkfat as the only fat in 		the product, with a milkfat content of 39 percent or more but less than 80 percent by weight. 3. Products obtained by the concentration of whey and with the addition of milk or milkfat are to be classified as cheese in heading 	0406 provided that they have the three following characteristics: 	(a) A milkfat content, by weight of the dry matter, of 5 percent or more; 	(b) A dry matter content, by weight, of at least 70 percent but not exceeding 85 percent; and 	(c) They are molded or capable of being molded. 4. This chapter does not cover: 	(a) Products cbtained from whey, containing by weight more than 95 percent lactose, expressed as anhydrous lactose calculated 		on the dry matter (heading 1702); or 	(b) Albumins (including concentrates of two or more whey proteins, containing by weight more than 80 percent whey proteins, 		calculated on the dry matter) (heading 3502) or globulins (heading 3504).  Subheading Note 1. For the purposes of subheading 0404.10, the expression "modified whey" means products consisting of whey constituents, that is, whey from which all or part of the lactose, proteins or minerals have been removed, whey to which natural whey constituents have been added, and products obtained by mixing natural whey constituents. 2. For the purposes of subheading 0405.10 the term "butter" does not include dehydrated butter or ghee (subheading 0405.90). 
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN05</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN05</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes: 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Edible products (other than guts, bladders and stomachs of animals, whole and pieces thereof, and animal blood, liquid or dried); (b) Hides or skins (including furskins) other than goods of heading 0505 and parings and similar waste of raw hides or skins of 	heading 0511 (chapter 41 or 43); (c) Animal textile materials, other than horsehair and horsehair waste (section XI); or (d) Prepared knots or tufts for broom or brush making (heading 9603). 2. For the purposes of heading 0501, the sorting of hair by length (provided the root ends and tip ends, respectively, are not arranged 	together) shall be deemed not to constitute working. 3. Throughout the tariff schedule, elephant, hippopotamus, walrus, narwhal and wild boar tusks, rhinoceros horns and the teeth of 	all animals are regarded as "ivory." 4. Throughout the tariff schedule, the expression "horsehair" means hair of the manes or tails of equine or bovine animals.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN06</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN06</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. Subject to the second part of heading 0601, this chapter covers only live trees and goods (including seedling vegetables) of a 	kind commonly supplied by nursery gardeners or florists for planting or for ornamental use; nevertheless it does not include 	potatoes, onions, shallots, garlic or other products of chapter 7. 2. Any reference in heading 0603 or 0604 to goods of any kind shall be construed as including a reference to bouquets, floral 	baskets, wreaths and similar articles made wholly or partly of goods of that kind, account not being taken of accessories of other 	materials. However, these headings do not apply to collages or similar decorative plaques of heading 9701.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN07</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN07</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover forage products of heading 1214. 2. In headings 0709, 0710, 0711 and 0712 the word "vegetables" includes edible mushrooms, truffles, olives, capers, marrows, 	pumpkins, eggplants (aubergines), sweet corn (Zea mays var. saccharata), fruits of the genus Capsicum (peppers) or of the 	genus Pimenta (e.g., allspice), fennel, parsley, chervil, tarragon, cress and sweet marjoram (Marjorana hortensis or Origanum 	marjorana). 3. Heading 0712 covers all dried vegetables of the kinds falling in headings 0701 to 0711, other than: (a) Dried leguminous vegetables, shelled (heading 0713); (b) Sweet corn in the forms specified in headings 1102 to 1104; (c) Flour, meal, powder, flakes, granules and pellets of potatoes (heading 1105); (d) Flour, meal and powder of the dried leguminous vegetables of heading 0713 (heading 1106). 4. However, dried or crushed or ground fruits of the genus Capsicum (peppers) or of the genus Pimenta (e.g., allspice) are excluded 	from this chapter (heading 0904).
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN08</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN08</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover inedible nuts or fruit. 2. Chilled fruit and nuts are to be classified in the same headings as the corresponding fresh fruit and nuts. 3. Dried fruit or dried nuts of this chapter may be partially rehydrated, or treated for the following purposes: (a) For additional preservation or stabilization (for example, by moderate heat treatment, sulfuring, the addition of sorbic acid 	or potassium sorbate), (b) To improve or maintain their appearance (for example, by the addition of vegetable oil or small quantities of glucose syrup), 	provided that they retain the character of dried fruits or dried nuts.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN09</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN09</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. Mixtures of the products of headings 0904 to 0910 are to be classified as follows: (a) Mixtures of two or more of the products of the same heading are to be classified in that heading; (b) Mixtures of two or more of the products of different headings are to be classified in heading 0910. 	The addition of other substances to the products of headings 0904 to 0910 (or to the mixtures referred to in paragraph (a) or (b) 	above) shall not affect their classification provided the resulting mixtures retain the essential character of the goods of those 	headings. Otherwise such mixtures are not classified in this chapter; those constituting mixed condiments or mixed seasonings 	are classified in heading 2103. 2. This chapter does not cover Cubeb pepper (Piper cubeba) or other products of heading 1211.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN10</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN10</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1.	(a) The products specified in the headings of this chapter are to be classified in those headings only if grains are present, whether 	or not in the ear or on the stalk. 	(b) This chapter does not cover grains which have been hulled or otherwise worked. However, rice, husked, milled, polished, 	glazed, parboiled or broken remains classified in heading 1006. 2. Heading 1005 does not cover sweet corn (chapter 7).  Subheading Note 1. The term " durum wheat" means wheat of the Triticum durum species and the hybrids derived from the interspecific crossing of Triticum durum which have the same number (28) of chromosomes as that species.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN11</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN11</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Roasted malt put up as coffee substitutes (heading 0901 or 2101); (b) Prepared flours, groats, meals or starches of heading 1901; (c) Corn flakes or other products of heading 1904; (d) Vegetables, prepared or preserved, of heading 2001, 2004 or 2005; (e) Pharmaceutical products (chapter 30); or (f) Starches having the character of perfumery, cosmetic or toilet preparations (chapter 33). 2. (A) Products from the milling of the cereals listed in the table below fall within this chapter if they have, by weight on the dry 	product: 		(a) A starch content (determined by the modified Ewers polarimetric method) exceeding that indicated in column (2); and 		(b) An ash content (after deduction of any added minerals) not exceeding that indicated in column (3). 		Otherwise, they fall in heading 2302. However, germ of cereals, whole, rolled, flaked or ground is always classified in heading 		1104. 	(B) Products falling within this chapter under the above provisions shall be classified in heading 1101 or 1102 if the percentage 	passing through a woven metal wire cloth sieve with the aperture indicated in column (4) or (5) is not less, by weight, than 	that shown against the cereal concerned. 	Otherwise, they fall in heading 1103 or 1104. _____________________________________________________________________________________________________ Cereal			Starch content	Ash content		Rate of passage through a sieve with an aperture of 												315 micrometres (microns)	500 micrometres (microns) (1)				(2)				(3)				(4)							(5) _____________________________________________________________________________________________________ Wheat and rye 	45%			  2.5%				80%							- Barley 			45%				3%				80%							- Oats 			45%				5%				80%							- Maize (corn) and  grain sorghum	45%				2%				-							90% Rice 			45%			  1.6%				80%							- Buckwheat 		45%				4%				80%							- _____________________________________________________________________________________________________  3. For the purposes of heading 1103 the terms "groats" and "meal" mean products obtained by the fragmentation of cereal grains, 	of which -- (a) In the case of corn (maize) products, at least 95 percent by weight passes through a woven metal wire cloth sieve with an 	aperture of 2 mm; (b) In the case of other cereal products, at least 95 percent by weight passes through a woven metal wirecloth sieve with an 	aperture of 1.25 mm.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN12</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN12</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. Heading 1207 applies, inter alia, to palm nuts and kernels, cotton seeds, castor oil seeds, sesame seeds, mustard seeds, safflower 	seeds, poppy seeds and shea nuts (karite nuts). It does not apply to products of heading 0801 or 0802 or to olives (chapter 7 or 	chapter 20). 2. Heading 1208 applies not only to non-defatted flours and meals but also to flours and meals which have been partially defatted 	or defatted and wholly or partially refatted with their original oils. It does not, however, apply to residues of headings 2304 to 	2306. 3. For the purposes of heading 1209, beet seeds, grass and other herbage seeds, seeds of ornamental flowers, vegetable seeds, 	seeds of forest trees, seeds of fruit trees, seeds of vetches (other than those of the species Vicia faba ) or of lupines are to be 	regarded as "seeds of a kind used for sowing". 	Heading 1209 does not, however, apply to the following even if for sowing: 	(a) Leguminous vegetables or sweet corn (chapter 7); 	(b) Spices or other products of chapter 9; 	(c) Cereals (chapter 10); or 	(d) Products of headings 1201 to 1207 or of heading 1211. 4. Heading 1211 applies, inter alia , to the following plants or parts thereof: basil, borage, ginseng, hyssop, licorice, all species of 	mint, rosemary, rue, sage and wormwood. 	Heading 1211 does not, however, apply to: 	(a) Medicaments of chapter 30; 	(b) Perfumery, cosmetic or toilet preparations of chapter 33; or 	(c) Insecticides, fungicides, herbicides, disinfectants or similar products of heading 3808. 5. For the purposes of heading 1212, the term "seaweeds and other algae" does not include: 	(a) Dead single-cell microorganisms of heading 2102; 	(b) Cultures of microorganisms of heading 3002; or 	(c) Fertilizers of heading 3101 or 3105.  Subheading Note 1. For the purposes of subheading 1205.10, the expression "low erucic acid rape or colza seeds" means rape or colza seeds yielding a fixed oil which has an erucic acid content of less than 2 percent by weight and yielding a solid component which contains less than 30 micromoles of glucosinolates per gram.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN13</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN13</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Note 1. Heading 1302 applies, inter alia, to licorice extract and extract of pyrethrum, extract of hops, extract of aloes and opium. The heading does not apply to: (a) Licorice extract containing more than 10 percent by weight of sucrose or put up as confectionery (heading 1704); (b) Malt extract (heading 1901); (c) Extracts of coffee, tea or maté (heading 2101); (d) Vegetable saps or extracts constituting alcoholic beverages (chapter 22); (e) Camphor, glycyrrhizin or other products of heading 2914 or 2938; (f) Concentrates of poppy straw containing not less than 50 percent by weight of alkaloids (heading 2939); (g) Medicaments of heading 3003 or 3004 or blood-grouping reagents (heading 3006); (h) Tanning or dyeing extracts (heading 3201 or 3203); (ij) Essential oils, concretes, absolutes, resinoids, extracted oleoresins, aqueous distillates or aqueous solutions of essential 	oils or preparations based on odoriferous substances of a kind used for the manufacture of beverages (chapter 33); or (k) Natural rubber, balata, gutta-percha, guayule, chicle or similar natural gums (heading 4001).
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN14</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN14</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover the following products which are to be classified in section XI: vegetable materials or fibers of 	vegetable materials of a kind used primarily in the manufacture of textiles, however prepared, or other vegetable materials which 	have undergone treatment so as to render them suitable for use only as textile materials. 2. Heading 1401 applies, inter alia, to bamboos (whether or not split, sawn lengthwise, cut to length, rounded at the ends, bleached, 	rendered nonflammable, polished or dyed), split osier, reeds and the like, to rattan cores and to drawn or split rattans. The 	heading does not apply to chipwood (heading 4404). 3. Heading 1404 does not apply to wood wool (heading 4405) and prepared knots or tufts for broom or brush making (heading 	9603).
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN15</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN15</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Pig fat or poultry fat, of heading 0209; (b) Cocoa butter, fat or oil (heading 1804); (c) Edible preparations containing by weight more than 15 percent of the products of heading 0405 (generally chapter 21); (d) Greaves (heading 2301) or residues of headings 2304 to 2306; (e) Fatty acids, prepared waxes, medicaments, paints, varnishes, soap, perfumery, cosmetic or toilet preparations, sulfonated 	oils or other goods of section VI; or (f) Factice derived from oils (heading 4002). 2. Heading 1509 does not apply to oils obtained from olives by solvent extraction (heading 1510). 3. Heading 1518 does not cover fats or oils or their fractions, merely denatured, which are to be classified in the heading appropriate 	to the corresponding undenatured fats and oils and their fractions. 4. Soap-stocks, oil foots and dregs, stearin pitch, glycerol pitch and wool grease residues fall in heading 1522.  Subheading Note 1. For the purposes of subheadings 1514.11 and 1514.19, the expression “low erucic acid rape or colza oil” means the fixed oil which has an erucic acid content of less than 2 percent by weight.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN16</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN16</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover meat, meat offal, fish, crustaceans, molluscs or other aquatic invertebrates, prepared or preserved 	 2. Food preparations fall in this chapter provided that they contain more than 20 percent by weight of sausage, meat, meat offal, 	blood, fish or crustaceans, molluscs or other aquatic invertebrates, or any combination thereof. In cases where the preparation 	contains two or more of the products mentioned above, it is classified in the heading of chapter 16 corresponding to the component 	or components which predominate by weight. These provisions do not apply to the stuffed products of heading 1902 or to the 	preparations of heading 2103 or 2104.  Subheading Notes 1. For the purposes of subheading 1602.10, the expression "homogenized preparations" means preparations of meat, meat offal 	or blood, finely homogenized, put up for retail sale as infant food or for dietetic purposes, in containers of a net weight content 	not exceeding 250 g. For the application of this definition no account is to be taken of small quantities of any ingredients which 	may have been added to the preparation for seasoning, preservation or other purposes. These preparations may contain a small 	quantity of visible pieces of meat or meat offal. This subheading takes precedence over all other subheadings of heading 1602. 2. The fish, crustaceans, molluscs and other aquatic invertebrates specified in the subheadings of heading 1604 or 1605 under 	their common names only, are of the same species as those mentioned in chapter 3 under the same name.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN17</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN17</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Note 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Sugar confectionery containing cocoa (heading 1806); (b) Chemically pure sugars (other than sucrose, lactose, maltose, glucose and fructose) or other products of heading 2940; or (c) Medicaments or other products of chapter 30.  Subheading Notes 1. For the purposes of subheadings 1701.12, 1701.13 and 1701.14, "raw sugar" means sugar whose content of sucrose by weight, 	in the dry state, corresponds to a polarimeter reading of less than 99.5 degrees. 2. Subheading 1701.13 covers only cane sugar obtained without centrifugation, whose content of sucrose by weight, in the dry 	state, corresponds to a polarimeter reading of 69° or more but less than 93°. The product contains only natural anhedral 	microcrystals, of irregular shape, not visible to the naked eye, which are surrounded by residues of molasses and other constituents 	of sugar cane.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN18</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN18</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover the preparations of heading 0403, 1901, 1904, 1905, 2105, 2202, 2208, 3003 or 3004. 2. Heading 1806 includes sugar confectionery containing cocoa, and, subject to note 1 to this chapter, other food preparations 	containing cocoa.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN19</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN19</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Except in the case of stuffed products of heading 1902, food preparations containing more than 20 percent by weight of 	sausage, meat, meat offal, blood, fish or crustaceans, molluscs or other aquatic invertebrates, or any combination thereof 	(chapter 16); (b) Biscuits or other articles made from flour or from starch, specially prepared for use in animal feeding (heading 2309); or (c) Medicaments or other products of chapter 30. 2. For the purposes of heading 1901: (a) The term "groats" means cereal groats of chapter 11; (b) The terms "flour" and "meal" mean : 	(1) Cereal flour and meal of chapter 11, and 	(2) Flour, meal and powder of vegetable origin of any chapter, other than flour, meal or powder of dried vegetables (heading 	0712), of potatoes (heading 1105) or of dried leguminous vegetables (heading 1106). 3. Heading 1904 does not cover preparations containing more than 6 percent by weight of cocoa calculated on a totally defatted 	basis or completely coated with chocolate or other food preparations containing cocoa of heading 1806 (heading 1806). 4. For the purposes of heading 1904 the expression "otherwise prepared" means prepared or processed to an extent beyond that 	provided for in the headings of or notes to chapter 10 or 11.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN20</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN20</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Vegetables, fruit or nuts, prepared or preserved by the processes specified in chapter 7, 8 or 11; (b) Food preparations containing more than 20 percent by weight of sausage, meat, meat offal, blood, fish or crustaceans, 	molluscs or other aquatic invertebrates, or any combination thereof (chapter 16); (c) Bakers' wares and other products of heading 1905; or (d) Homogenized composite food preparations of heading 2104. 2. Headings 2007 and 2008 do not apply to fruit jellies, fruit pastes, sugar-coated almonds or the like in the form of sugar confectionery 	(heading 1704) or chocolate confectionery (heading 1806). 3. Heading 2001, 2004 and 2005 cover, as the case may be, only those products of chapter 7 or of heading 1105 or 1106 (other 	than flour, meal and powder of the products of chapter 8), which have been prepared or preserved by processes other than those 	referred to in note 1(a). 4. Tomato juice the dry weight content of which is 7 percent or more is to be classified in heading 2002. 5. For the purposes of heading 2007, the expression " obtained by cooking" means obtained by heat treatment at atmospheric 	pressure or under reduced pressure to increase the viscosity of a product through reduction of water content or other means. 6. For the purposes of heading 2009 the expression "juices, unfermented and not containing added spirit" means juices of an 	alcoholic strength by volume (see note 2 to chapter 22) not exceeding 0.5 percent vol.  Subheading Notes 1. For the purposes of subheading 2005.10, the expression "homogenized vegetables" means preparations of vegetables, finely 	homogenized, put up for retail sale as infant food or for dietetic purposes, in containers of a net weight content not exceeding 	250 g. For the application of this definition no account is to be taken of small quantities of any ingredients which may have been 	added to the preparation for seasoning, preservation or other purposes. These preparations may contain a small quantity of 	visible pieces of vegetables. Subheading 2005.10 takes precedence over all other subheadings of heading 2005. 2. For the purposes of subheading 2007.10, the expression "homogenized preparations" means preparations of fruit, finely 	homogenized, put up for retail sale as infant food or for dietetic purposes, in containers of a net weight content not exceeding 	250 g. For the application of this definition no account is to be taken of small quantities of any ingredients which may have been 	added to the preparation for seasoning, preservation or other purposes. These preparations may contain a small quantity of 	visible pieces of fruit. Subheading 2007.10 takes precedence over all other subheadings of heading 2007. 3. For the purposes of subheadings 2009.12, 2009.21, 2009.31, 2009.41, 2009.61 and 2009.71, the expression " Brix value" means 	the direct reading of degrees Brix obtained from a Brix hydrometer or of refractive index expressed in terms of percentage sucrose 	content obtained from a refractometer, at a temperature of 20 °C or corrected for 20 °C if the reading is made at a different 	temperature.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN21</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN21</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Mixed vegetables of heading 0712; (b) Roasted coffee substitutes containing coffee in any proportion (heading 0901); (c) Flavored tea (heading 0902); (d) Spices or other products of headings 0904 to 0910; (e) Food preparations, other than the products described in heading 2103 or 2104, containing more than 20 percent by weight 	of sausage, meat, meat offal, blood, fish or crustaceans, molluscs or other aquatic invertebrates, or any combination thereof 	(chapter 16); (f) Yeast put up as a medicament or other products of heading 3003 or 3004; or (g) Prepared enzymes of heading 3507. 2. Extracts of the substitutes referred to in note 1(b) above are to be classified in heading 2101. 3. For the purposes of heading 2104, the expression "homogenized composite food preparations" means preparations consisting 	of a finely homogenized mixture of two or more basic ingredients such as meat, fish, vegetables, fruit or nuts, put up for retail 	sale as infant food or for dietetic purposes, in containers of a net weight content not exceeding 250 g. For the application of this 	definition, no account is to be taken of small quantities of any ingredients which may be added to the mixture for seasoning, 	preservation or other purposes. Such preparations may contain a small quantity of visible pieces of ingredients.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN22</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN22</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Products of this chapter (other than those of heading 2209) prepared for culinary purposes and thereby rendered unsuitable 	for consumption as beverages (generally heading 2103) (b) Sea water (heading 2501); (c) Distilled or conductivity water or water of similar purity (heading 2853); (d) Acetic acid of a concentration exceeding 10 percent by weight of acetic acid (heading 2915); (e) Medicaments of heading 3003 or 3004; or (f) Perfumery or toilet preparations (chapter 33). 2. For the purposes of this chapter and of chapters 20 and 2l, the "alcoholic strength by volume" shall be determined at a temperature 	of 20°C. 3. For the purposes of heading 2202 the term "nonalcoholic beverages" means beverages of an alcoholic strength by volume not 	exceeding 0.5 percent vol. Alcoholic beverages are classified in headings 2203 to 2206 or heading 2208 as appropriate.  Subheading Note 1. For the purposes of subheading 2204.10 the expression "sparkling wine" means wine which, when kept at a temperature of 20°C 	in closed containers, has an excess pressure of not less than 3 bars.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN23</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN23</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Note 1. Heading 2309 includes products of a kind used in animal feeding, not elsewhere specified or included, obtained by processing 	vegetable or animal materials to such an extent that they have lost the essential characteristics of the original material, other 	than vegetable waste, vegetable residues and byproducts of such processing.  Subheading Note 1. For the purposes of subheading 2306.41, the expression " low erucic acid rape or colza seeds" means seeds as defined in 	subheading note 1 to chapter 12.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN24</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN24</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Note 1. This chapter does not cover medicinal cigarettes (chapter 30).  Subheading Note 1. For the purposes of subheading 2403.11.00, the expression "water pipe tobacco" means tobacco intended for smoking in a water 	pipe and which consists of a mixture of tobacco and glycerol, whether or not containing aromatic oils and extracts, molasses or 	sugar, and whether or not flavored with fruit. However, tobacco-free products intended for smoking in a water pipe are excluded 	from this subheading.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN25</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN25</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. Except where their context or note 4 to this chapter otherwise requires, the headings of this chapter cover only products which 	are in the crude state or which have been washed (even with chemical substances eliminating the impurities without changing 	the structure of the product), crushed, ground, powdered, levigated, sifted, screened, concentrated by flotation, magnetic separation 	or other mechanical or physical processes (except crystallization), but not products which have been roasted, calcined, obtained 	by mixing or subjected to processing beyond that mentioned in each heading. 	The products of this chapter may contain an added anti-dusting agent, provided that such addition does not render the product 	particularly suitable for a specific use rather than for general use. 2. This chapter does not cover: (a) Sublimed sulfur, precipitated sulfur or colloidal sulfur (heading 2802); (b) Earth colors containing 70 percent or more by weight of combined iron evaluated as Fe2O3 (heading 282l); (c) Medicaments or other products of chapter 30; (d) Perfumery, cosmetic or toilet preparations (chapter 33); (e) Setts, curbstones or flagstones (heading 6801); mosaic cubes and the like (heading 6802); roofing, facing or damp course 	slates (heading 6803); (f) Precious or semiprecious stones (heading 7102 or 7103); (g) Cultured crystals (other than optical elements) weighing not less than 2.5 g each, of sodium chloride or of magnesium oxide, 	of heading 3824; optical elements of sodium chloride or of magnesium oxide (heading 9001); (h) Billiard chalks (heading 9504); or (ij) Writing or drawing chalks or tailors' chalks (heading 9609). 3. Any products classifiable in heading 2517 and any other heading of the chapter are to be classified in heading 2517. 4. Heading 2530 applies, inter alia, to: vermiculite, perlite and chlorites, unexpanded; earth colors, whether or not calcined or mixed 	together; natural micaceous iron oxides; meerschaum (whether or not in polished pieces); amber; agglomerated meerschaum 	and agglomerated amber, in plates, rods, sticks or similar forms, not worked after molding; jet; strontianite (whether or not 	calcined), other than strontium oxide; broken pieces of pottery, brick or concrete.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN26</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN26</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Slag or similar industrial waste prepared as macadam (heading 2517); (b) Natural magnesium carbonate (magnesite), whether or not calcined (heading 2519); (c) Sludges from the storage tanks of petroleum oils, consisting mainly of such oils (heading 2710); (d) Basic slag of chapter 31; (e) Slag wool, rock wool or similar mineral wools (heading 6806); (f) Waste or scrap of precious metal or of metal clad with precious metal; other waste or scrap containing precious metal or 	precious metal compounds, of a kind used principally for the recovery of precious metal (heading 7112); or (g) Copper, nickel or cobalt mattes produced by any process of smelting (section XV). 2. For the purposes of headings 2601 to 2617, the term "ores" means minerals of mineralogical species actually used in the 	metallurgical industry for the extraction of mercury, of the metals of heading 2844 or of the metals of section XIV or XV, even if 	they are intended for non-metallurgical purposes. Headings 2601 to 2617 do not, however, include minerals which have been 	submitted to processes not normal to the metallurgical industry. 3. Heading 2620 applies only to: (a) Slag, ash and residues of a kind used in industry either for the extraction of metals or as a basis for the manufacture of 	chemical compounds of metals, excluding ash and residues from the incineration of municipal waste (heading 2621); and (b) Slag, ash and residues containing arsenic, whether or not containing metals, of a kind used either for the extraction of arsenic 	or metals or for the manufacture of their chemical compounds.  Subheading Notes 1. For the purposes of subheading 2620.21.00, "leaded gasoline sludges and leaded anti-knock compound sludges" means sludges 	obtained from storage tanks of leaded gasoline and leaded anti-knock compounds (for example, tetraethyl lead), and consisting 	essentially of lead, lead compounds and iron oxide. 2. Slag, ash and residues containing arsenic, mercury, thallium or their mixtures, of a kind used for the extraction of arsenic or 	those metals or for the manufacture of their chemical compounds, are to be classified in subheading 2620.60.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN27</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN27</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Separate chemically defined organic compounds, other than pure methane and propane which are to be classified in heading 	2711; (b) Medicaments of heading 3003 or 3004; or (c) Mixed unsaturated hydrocarbons of heading 3301, 3302 or 3805. 2. References in heading 2710 to "petroleum oils and oils obtained from bituminous minerals" include not only petroleum oils and 	oils obtained from bituminous minerals, but also similar oils, as well as those consisting mainly of mixed unsaturated hydrocarbons, 	obtained by any process, provided that the weight of the nonaromatic constituents exceeds that of the aromatic constituents. 	However, the references do not include liquid synthetic polyolefins of which less than 60 percent by volume distills at 300°C, after 	conversion to 1,013 millibars when a reduced-pressure distillation method is used (chapter 39). 3. For the purposes of heading 2710, "waste oils" means waste containing mainly petroleum oils and oils obtained from bituminous 	minerals (as described in note 2 to this chapter), whether or not mixed with water. These include: (a) Such oils no longer fit for use as primary products (for example, used lubricating oils, used hydraulic oils and used transformer 	oils); (b) Sludge oils from the storage tanks of petroleum oils, mainly containing such oils and a high concentration of additives (for 	example, chemicals) used in the manufacture of the primary products; and (c) Such oils in the form of emulsions in water or mixtures with water, such as those resulting from oil spills, storage tank 	washings, or from the use of cutting oils for machining operations.  Subheading Notes 1. For the purposes of subheading 2701.11, "anthracite" means coal having a volatile matter limit (on a dry, mineral-matter-free 	basis) not exceeding 14 percent. 2. For the purposes of subheading 2701.12, "bituminous coal" means coal having a volatile matter limit (on a dry, mineral-matter-free 	basis) exceeding 14 percent and a calorific value limit (on a moist, mineral-matter-free basis) equal to or greater than 5,833 	kcal/kg. 3. For the purposes of subheadings 2707.10, 2707.20, 2707.30, 2707.40, the terms "benzol (benzene)", "toluol (toluene)", "xylol 	(xylenes)" and "naphthalene" apply to products which contain more than 50 percent by weight of benzene, toluene, xylenes or 	naphthalene, respectively. 4. For the purposes of subheading 2710.12, "light oils and preparations" are those of which 90 percent or more by volume (including 	losses) distill at 210°C (ASTM D 86 method).
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN28</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN28</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. Except where the context otherwise requires, the headings of this chapter apply only to: (a) Separate chemical elements and separate chemically defined compounds, whether or not containing impurities; (b) The products mentioned in (a) above dissolved in water; (c) The products mentioned in (a) above dissolved in other solvents provided that the solution constitutes a normal and necessary 	method of putting up these products adopted solely for reasons of safety or for transport and that the solvent does not render 	the product particularly suitable for specific use rather than for general use; (d) The products mentioned in (a), (b) or (c) above with an added stabilizer (including an anticaking agent) necessary for their 	preservation or transport; (e) The products mentioned in (a), (b), (c) or (d) above with an added antidusting agent or a coloring substance added to facilitate 	their identification or for safety reasons, provided that the additions do not render the product particularly suitable for specific 	use rather than for general use. 2. In addition to dithionites and sulfoxylates, stabilized with organic substances (heading 2831), carbonates and peroxocarbonates 	of inorganic bases (heading 2836), cyanides, cyanide oxides and complex cyanides of inorganic bases (heading 2837), fulminates, 	cyanates and thiocyanates, of inorganic bases (heading 2842), organic products included in headings 2843 to 2846 and 2852 	and carbides (heading 2849), only the following compounds of carbon are to be classified in this chapter: (a) Oxides of carbon, hydrogen cyanide and fulminic, isocyanic, thiocyanic and other simple or complex cyanogen acids (heading 	2811); (b) Halide oxides of carbon (heading 2812); (c) Carbon disulfide (heading 2813); (d) Thiocarbonates, selenocarbonates, tellurocarbonates, selenocyanates, tellurocyanates, tetrathiocyanatodiamminochromates 	(reineckates) and other complex cyanates, of inorganic bases (heading 2842); (e) Hydrogen peroxide, solidified with urea (heading 2847), carbon oxysulfide, thiocarbonyl halides, cyanogen, cyanogen halides 	and cyanamide and its metal derivatives (heading 2853) other than calcium cyanamide, whether or not pure (chapter 31). 3. Subject to the provisions of note 1 to section VI, this chapter does not cover: (a) Sodium chloride or magnesium oxide, whether or not pure, or other products of section V; (b) Organo-inorganic compounds other than those mentioned in note 2 above; (c) Products mentioned in note 2, 3, 4 or 5 to chapter 31; (d) Inorganic products of a kind used as luminophores, of heading 3206; glass frit and other glass in the form of powder, granules 	or flakes, of heading 3207; (e) Artificial graphite (heading 3801); products put up as charges for fire-extinguishers or put up in fire-extinguishing grenades, 	of heading 3813; ink removers put up in packings for retail sale, of heading 3824; cultured crystals (other than optical 	elements) weighing not less than 2.5 g each, of the halides of the alkali or alkaline-earth metals, of heading 3824; (f) Precious or semiprecious stones (natural, synthetic or reconstructed) or dust or powder of such stones (headings 7102 to 	7105), or precious metals or precious metal alloys of chapter 71; (g) The metals, whether or not pure, metal alloys or cermets, including sintered metal carbides (metal carbides sintered with a 	metal), of section XV; or (h) Optical elements, for example, of the halides of the alkali or alkaline-earth metals (heading 9001). 4. Chemically defined complex acids consisting of a nonmetal acid of subchapter II and a metal acid of subchapter IV are to be 	classified in heading 2811. 5. Headings 2826 to 2842 apply only to metal or ammonium salts or peroxysalts. 	Except where the context otherwise requires, double or complex salts are to be classified in heading 2842. 6. Heading 2844 applies only to: (a) Technetium (atomic No. 43), promethium (atomic No. 61), polonium (atomic No. 84) and all elements with an atomic number 	greater than 84; (b) Natural or artificial radioactive isotopes (including those of the precious metals or of the base metals of sections XIV and 	XV), whether or not mixed together; (c) Compounds, inorganic or organic, of these elements or isotopes, whether or not chemically defined, whether or not mixed 	together; (d) Alloys, dispersions (including cermets), ceramic products and mixtures containing these elements or isotopes or inorganic 	or organic compounds thereof and having a specific radioactivity exceeding 74 becquerels per gram (0.002 microcurie per 	gram); (e) Spent (irradiated) fuel elements (cartridges) of nuclear reactors; (f) Radioactive residues whether or not usable. 	The term "isotopes", for the purposes of this note and of the wording of headings 2844 and 2845, refers to: 	(i) Individual nuclides, excluding, however, those existing in nature in the monoiosotopic state; 	(ii) Mixtures of isotopes of one and the same element, enriched in one or several of the said isotopes, that is, elements 	of which the natural isotopic composition has been artificially modified. 7. Heading 2848 includes copper phosphide (phosphor copper) containing more than 15 percent by weight of phosphorus. 8. Chemical elements (for example, silicon and selenium) doped for use in electronics are to be classified in this chapter, provided 	that they are in forms unworked as drawn, or in the form of cylinders or rods. When cut in the form of discs, wafers or similar 	forms, they fall in heading 3818.  Subheading Note 1. For the purposes of subheading 2852.10, the expression "chemically defined" means all organic or inorganic compounds of 	mercury meeting the requirements of paragraphs (a) to (e) of Note 1 to Chapter 28 or paragraphs (a) to (h) of Note 1 to Chapter 	29.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN29</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN29</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. Except where the context otherwise requires, the headings of this chapter apply only to: (a) Separate chemically defined organic compounds, whether or not containing impurities; (b) Mixtures of two or more isomers of the same organic compound (whether or not containing impurities), except mixtures of 	acyclic hydrocarbon isomers (other than stereoisomers), whether or not saturated (chapter 27); (c) The products of headings 2936 to 2939 or the sugar ethers, sugar acetals and sugar esters, and their salts, of heading 2940, 	or the products of heading 2941, whether or not chemically defined; (d) Products mentioned in (a), (b) or (c) above dissolved in water; (e) Products mentioned in (a), (b) or (c) above dissolved in other solvents provided that the solution constitutes a normal and 	necessary method of putting up these products adopted solely for reasons of safety or for transport and that the solvent 	does not render the product particularly suitable for specific use rather than for general use; (f) The products mentioned in (a), (b), (c), (d) or (e) above with an added stabilizer (including an anticaking agent) necessary 	for their preservation or transport; (g) The products mentioned in (a), (b), (c), (d), (e) or (f) above with an added antidusting agent or a coloring or odoriferous 	substance added to facilitate their identification or for safety reasons, provided that the additions do not render the product 	particularly suitable for specific use rather than for general use; (h) The following products, diluted to standard strengths, for the production of azo dyes: diazonium salts, couplers used for 	these salts and diazotizable amines and their salts. 2. This chapter does not cover: (a) Goods of heading 1504 or crude glycerol of heading 1520; (b) Ethyl alcohol (heading 2207 or 2208); (c) Methane or propane (heading 2711); (d) The compounds of carbon mentioned in note 2 to chapter 28; (e) Immunological products of heading 3002; (f) Urea (heading 3102 or 3105); (g) Coloring matter of vegetable or animal origin (heading 3203), synthetic organic coloring matter, synthetic organic products 	of a kind used as fluorescent brightening agents or as luminophores (heading 3204) and dyes or other coloring matter put 	up in forms or packings for retail sale (heading 3212); (h) Enzymes (heading 3507); (ij) Metaldehyde, hexamethylenetetramine or similar substances put up in forms (for example, tablets, sticks or similar forms) 	for use as fuels, or liquid or liquefied-gas fuels in containers of a kind used for filling or refilling cigarette or similar lighters, 	and of a capacity not exceeding 300 cm3 (heading 3606); (k) Products put up as charges for fire extinguishers or put up in fire-extinguishing grenades, of heading 3813; ink removers put 	up in packings for retail sale, of heading 3824; or (l) Optical elements, for example, of ethylenediamine tartrate (heading 9001). 3. Goods which could be included in two or more of the headings of this chapter are to be classified in that one of those headings 	which occurs last in numerical order. 4. In headings 2904 to 2906, 2908 to 2911 and 2913 to 2920, any reference to halogenated, sulfonated, nitrated or nitrosated 	derivatives includes a reference to compound derivatives, such as sulfohalogenated, nitrohalogenated, nitrosulfonated or 	nitrosulfohalogenated derivatives. 	Nitro or nitroso groups are not to be taken as "nitrogen-functions" for the purposes of heading 2929. 	For the purposes of headings 2911, 2912, 2914, 2918 and 2922, "oxygen-function" is to be restricted to the functions (the 	characteristic organic oxygen-containing groups) referred to in headings 2905 to 2920. 5.	(A) The esters of acid-function organic compounds of subchapters I to VII with organic compounds of these subchapters are to 		be classified with that compound which is classified in the heading placed last in numerical order in these subchapters. 	(B) Esters of ethyl alcohol with acid-function organic compounds of subchapters I to VII are to be classified in the same heading 		as the corresponding acid-function compounds. 	(C) Subject to note l to section VI and note 2 to chapter 28: 		(1) Inorganic salts of organic compounds such as acid-, phenol- or enol-function compounds or organic bases, of subchapters 			I to X or heading 2942, are to be classified in the heading appropriate to the organic compound; 		(2) Salts formed between organic compounds of subchapters I to X or heading 2942 are to be classified in the heading 			appropriate to the base or to the acid (including phenol- or enol-function compounds) from which they are formed, 			whichever occurs last in numerical order in the chapter; and 		(3) Co-ordination compounds, other than products classifiable in subchapter XI or heading 2941, are to be classified in the 			heading which occurs last in numerical order in chapter 29, among those appropriate to the fragments formed by 			"cleaving" of all metal bonds, other than metal-carbon bonds. 	(D) Metal alcoholates are to be classified in the same heading as the corresponding alcohols except in the case of ethanol 		(heading 2905). 	(E) Halides of carboxylic acids are to be classified in the same heading as the corresponding acids. 6. The compounds of headings 2930 and 2931 are organic compounds the molecules of which contain, in addition to atoms of 	hydrogen, oxygen or nitrogen, atoms of other nonmetals or of metals (such as sulfur, arsenic or lead) directly linked to carbon 	atoms. 	Heading 2930 (organo-sulfur compounds) and heading 2931 (other organo-inorganic compounds) do not include sulfonated or 	halogenated derivatives (including compound derivatives) which, apart from hydrogen, oxygen and nitrogen, only have directly 	linked to carbon the atoms of sulfur or of a halogen which give them their nature of sulfonated or halogenated derivatives (or 	compound derivatives). 7. Headings 2932, 2933 and 2934 do not include epoxides with a three-membered ring, ketone peroxides, cyclic polymers of 	aldehydes or of thioaldehydes, anhydrides of polybasic carboxylic acids, cyclic esters of polyhydric alcohols or phenols with 	polybasic acids, or imides of polybasic acids. 	These provisions apply only when the ring-position hetero-atoms are those resulting solely from the cyclizing function or functions 	here listed. 8. For the purposes of heading 2937: (a) the term "hormones" includes hormone-releasing or hormone-stimulating factors, hormone inhibitors and hormone antagonists 	(antihormones); (b) the expression "used primarily as hormones" applies not only to hormone derivatives and structural analogues used primarily 	for their hormonal effect, but also to those derivatives and structural analogues used primarily as intermediates in the synthesis 	of products of this heading.  Subheading Notes 1. Within any one heading of this chapter, derivatives of a chemical compound (or group of chemical compounds) are to be classified 	in the same subheading as that compound (or group of compounds) provided that they are not more specifically covered by any 	other subheading and that there is no residual subheading named "Other" in the series of subheadings concerned. 2. Note 3 to chapter 29 does not apply to the subheadings of this chapter.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN30</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN30</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Foods or beverages (such as dietetic, diabetic or fortified foods, food supplements, tonic beverages and mineral waters), 	other than nutritional preparations for intravenous administration (section IV); (b) Preparations, such as tablets, chewing gum or patches (transdermal systems), intended to assist smokers to stop smoking 	(heading 2106 or 3824), (c) Plasters specially calcined or finely ground for use in dentistry (heading 2520); (d) Aqueous distillates or aqueous solutions of essential oils, suitable for medicinal uses (heading 3301); (e) Preparations of headings 3303 to 3307, even if they have therapeutic or prophylactic properties; (f) Soap or other products of heading 3401 containing added medicaments; (g) Preparations with a basis of plaster for use in dentistry (heading 3407); or (h) Blood albumin not prepared for therapeutic or prophylactic uses (heading 3502). 2. For the purposes of heading 3002, the expression "immunological products" applies to peptides and proteins (other than goods 	of heading 2937) which are directly involved in the regulation of immunological processes, such as monoclonal antibodies (MAB), 	antibody fragments, antibody conjugates and antibody fragment conjugates, interleukins, interferons (IFN), chemokines and 	certain tumor necrosis factors (TNF), growth factors (GF), hematopoietins and colony stimulating factors (CSF). 3. For the purposes of headings 3003 and 3004 and of note 4(d) to this chapter the following are to be treated-- (a) As unmixed products: 	(1) Unmixed products dissolved in water; 	(2) All goods of chapter 28 or 29; and 	(3) Simple vegetable extracts of heading 1302, merely standardized or dissolved in any solvent; (b) As products which have been mixed: 	(1) Colloidal solutions and suspensions (other than colloidal sulfur); 	(2) Vegetable extracts obtained by the treatment of mixtures of vegetable materials; and 	(3) Salts and concentrates obtained by evaporating natural mineral waters. 4. Heading 3006 applies only to the following, which are to be classified in that heading and in no other heading of the tariff schedule: (a) Sterile surgical catgut, similar sterile suture materials (including sterile absorbable surgical or dental yarns) and sterile tissue 	adhesives for surgical wound closure; (b) Sterile laminaria and sterile laminaria tents; (c) Sterile absorbable surgical or dental hemostatics, sterile surgical or dental adhesion barriers, whether or not absorbable; (d) Opacifying preparations for X-ray examinations and diagnostic reagents designed to be administered to the patient, being 	unmixed products put up in measured doses or products consisting of two or more ingredients which have been mixed 	together for such uses; (e) Blood-grouping reagents; (f) Dental cements and other dental fillings; bone reconstruction cements; (g) First-aid boxes and kits; (h) Chemical contraceptive preparations based on hormones, on other products of heading 2937 or on spermicides; (ij) Gel preparations designed to be used in human or veterinary medicine as a lubricant for parts of the body for surgical 	operations or physical examinations or as a coupling agent between the body and medical instruments; (k) Waste pharmaceuticals, that is, pharmaceutical products which are unfit for their original intended purpose, for example, 	because of expiry of shelf life; and (l) Appliances identifiable for ostomy use, that is, colostomy, ileostomy and urostomy pouches cut to shape and their adhesive 	wafers or faceplates.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN31</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN31</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Animal blood of heading 0511; (b) Separate chemically defined compounds (other than those answering to the descriptions in note 2(a), 3(a), 4(a) or 5, below); 	or (c) Cultured potassium chloride crystals (other than optical elements) weighing not less than 2.5 g each, of heading 3824; optical 	elements of potassium chloride (heading 9001). 2. Heading 3102 applies only to the following goods, provided that they are not put up in the forms or packages described in heading 	3105: (a) Goods which answer to one or other of the descriptions given below: 	(i) Sodium nitrate, whether or not pure; 	(ii) Ammonium nitrate, whether or not pure; 	(iii) Double salts (whether or not pure) of ammonium sulfate and ammonium nitrate; 	(iv) Ammonium sulfate, whether or not pure; 	(v) Double salts (whether or not pure) or mixtures of calcium nitrate and ammonium nitrate; 	(vi) Double salts (whether or not pure) or mixtures of calcium nitrate and magnesium nitrate; 	(vii) Calcium cyanamide, whether or not pure or treated with oil; 	(viii) Urea, whether or not pure. (b) Fertilizers consisting of any of the goods described in (a) above mixed together. (c) Fertilizers consisting of ammonium chloride or of any of the goods described in (a) or (b) above mixed with chalk, gypsum 	or other inorganic nonfertilizing substances. (d) Liquid fertilizers consisting of the goods of subparagraph (a)(ii) or (a)(viii) above, or of mixtures of those goods, in an aqueous 	or ammoniacal solution. 3. Heading 3103 applies only to the following goods, provided that they are not put up in the forms or packages described in heading 	3105: (a) Goods which answer to one or other of the descriptions given below: 	(i) Basic slag; 	(ii) Natural phosphates of heading 2510, calcined or further heat-treated than for the removal of impurities; 	(iii) Superphosphates (single, double or triple); 	(iv) Calcium hydrogenorthophosphate containing not less than 0.2 percent by weight of fluorine calculated on the dry 	anhydrous product. (b) Fertilizers consisting of any of the goods described in (a) above, mixed together, but with no account being taken of the 	fluorine content limit. (c) Fertilizers consisting of any of the goods described in (a) or (b) above, but with no account being taken of the fluorine content 	limit, mixed with chalk, gypsum or other inorganic nonfertilizing substances. 4. Heading 3104 applies only to the following goods, provided that they are not put up in the forms or packages described in heading 	3105: (a) Goods which answer to one or other of the descriptions given below: 	(i) Crude natural potassium salts (for example, carnallite, kainite and sylvite); 	(ii) Potassium chloride, whether or not pure, except as provided in note 1(c) above; 	(iii) Potassium sulfate, whether or not pure; 	(iv) Magnesium potassium sulfate, whether or not pure. (b) Fertilizers consisting of any of the goods described in (a) above mixed together. 5. Ammonium dihydrogenorthophosphate (monoammonium phosphate) and diammonium hydrogenorthophosphate (diammonium 	phosphate), whether or not pure, and intermediates thereof, are to be classified in heading 3105. 6. For the purposes of heading 3105, the term "other fertilizers" applies only to products of a kind used as fertilizers and containing, 	as an essential constituent, at least one of the fertilizing elements nitrogen, phosphorus or potassium.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN32</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN32</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Separate chemically defined elements or compounds (except those of heading 3203 or 3204, inorganic products of a kind 	used as luminophores (heading 3206), glass obtained from fused quartz or other fused silica in the forms provided for in 	heading 3207, and also dyes and other coloring matter put up in forms or packings for retail sale, of heading 3212); (b) Tannates or other tannin derivatives of products of headings 2936 to 2939, 2941 or 3501 to 3504; or (c) Mastics of asphalt or other bituminous mastics (heading 2715). 2. Heading 3204 includes mixtures of stabilized diazonium salts and couplers for the production of azo dyes. 3. Headings 3203, 3204, 3205 and 3206 apply also to preparations based on coloring matter (including, in the case of heading 	3206, coloring pigments of heading 2530 or chapter 28, metal flakes and metal powders), of a kind used for coloring any material 	or used as ingredients in the manufacture of coloring preparations. The headings do not apply, however, to pigments dispersed 	in nonaqueous media, in liquid or paste form, of a kind used in the manufacture of paints, including enamels (heading 3212), or 	to other preparations of heading 3207, 3208, 3209, 3210, 3212, 3213 or 3215. 4. Heading 3208 includes solutions (other than collodions) consisting of any of the products specified in headings 3901 to 3913 in 	volatile organic solvents when the weight of the solvent exceeds 50 percent of the weight of the solution. 5. The expression "coloring matter" in this chapter does not include products of a kind used as extenders in oil paints, whether or 	not they are also suitable for coloring distempers. 6. The expression "stamping foils" in heading 3212 applies only to thin sheets of a kind used for printing, for example, book covers 	or hat bands, and consisting of-- (a) Metallic powder (including powder of precious metal) or pigment, agglomerated with glue, gelatin or other binder; or (b) Metal (including precious metal) or pigment, deposited on a supporting sheet of any material.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN33</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN33</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Natural oleoresins or vegetable extracts of heading 1301 or 1302; (b) Soap or other products of heading 3401; or (c) Gum, wood or sulfate turpentine or other products of heading 3805. 2. The expression "odoriferous substances" in heading 3302 refers only to the substances of heading 3301, to odoriferous constituents 	isolated from those substances or to synthetic aromatics. 3. Headings 3303 to 3307 apply, inter alia, to products, whether or not mixed (other than aqueous distillates and aqueous solutions 	of essential oils), suitable for use as goods of these headings and put up in packings of a kind sold by retail for such use. 4. The expression "perfumery, cosmetic or toilet preparations" in heading 3307 applies, inter alia, to the following products: scented 	sachets; odoriferous preparations which operate by burning; perfumed papers and papers impregnated or coated with cosmetics; 	contact lens or artificial eye solutions; wadding, felt and nonwovens, impregnated, coated or covered with perfume or cosmetics; 	animal toilet preparations.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN34</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN34</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Edible mixtures or preparations of animal or vegetable fats or oils of a kind used as mold release preparations (heading 	1517); (b) Separate chemically defined compounds; or (c) Shampoos, dentifrices, shaving creams and foams or bath preparations, containing soap or other organic surface-active 	agents (heading 3305, 3306 or 3307). 2. For the purposes of heading 3401, the expression "soap" applies only to soap soluble in water. Soap and the other products of 	heading 3401 may contain added substances (for example, disinfectants, abrasive powders, fillers or medicaments). Products 	containing abrasive powders remain classified in heading 3401 only if in the form of bars, cakes or molded pieces or shapes. In 	other forms they are to be classified in heading 3405 as "scouring powders and similar preparations". 3. For the purposes of heading 3402, "organic surface-active agents" are products which when mixed with water at a concentration 	of 0.5 percent at 20°C and left to stand for one hour at the same temperature: (a) Give a transparent or translucent liquid or stable emulsion without separation of insoluble matter; and (b) Reduce the surface tension of water to 4.5 x 10 -2 N/m (45 dyne/cm) or less. 4. In heading 3403 the expression "petroleum oils and oils obtained from bituminous minerals" applies to the products defined in 	note 2 to chapter 27. 5. In heading 3404, subject to the exclusions provided below, the expression "artificial waxes and prepared waxes" applies only 	to: (a) Chemically produced organic products of a waxy character, whether or not water-soluble; (b) Products obtained by mixing different waxes; (c) Products of a waxy character with a basis of one or more waxes and containing fats, resins, mineral substances or other 	materials. The heading does not apply to: (a) Goods of heading 1516, 3402 or 3823 even if having a waxy character; (b) Unmixed animal waxes or unmixed vegetable waxes, whether or not refined or colored, of heading 1521; (c) Mineral waxes or similar products of heading 2712, whether or not intermixed or merely colored; or (d) Waxes mixed with, dispersed in or dissolved in a liquid medium (headings 3405, 3809, etc.).
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN35</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN35</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Yeasts (heading 2102); (b) Blood fractions (other than blood albumin not prepared for therapeutic or prophylactic uses), medicaments or other products 	of chapter 30; (c) Enzymatic preparations for pre-tanning (heading 3202); (d) Enzymatic soaking or washing preparations or other products of chapter 34; (e) Hardened proteins (heading 3913); or (f) Gelatin products of the printing industry (chapter 49). 2. For the purposes of heading 3505, the term "dextrins" means starch degradation products with a reducing sugar content, 	expressed as dextrose on the dry substance, not exceeding 10 percent. 	Such products with a reducing sugar content exceeding 10 percent fall in heading 1702.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN36</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN36</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover separate chemically defined compounds other than those described in note 2(a) or (b) below. 2. The expression "articles of combustible materials" in heading 3606 applies only to: (a) Metaldehyde, hexamethylenetetramine and similar substances, put up in forms (for example, tablets, sticks or similar forms) 	for use as fuels; fuels with a basis of alcohol, and similar prepared fuels, in solid or semi-solid form; (b) Liquid or liquefied-gas fuels in containers of a kind used for filling or refilling cigarette or similar lighters, and of a capacity 	not exceeding 300 cm 3; and (c) Resin torches, firelighters and the like.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN37</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN37</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover waste or scrap. 2. In this chapter the word "photographic" relates to the process by which visible images are formed, directly or indirectly, by the 	action of light or other forms of radiation on photosensitive surfaces.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN38</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN38</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Separate chemically defined elements or compounds with the exception of the following: 	(1) Artificial graphite (heading 3801); 	(2) Insecticides, rodenticides, fungicides, herbicides, antisprouting products and plant-growth regulators, disinfectants and 		similar products put up as described in heading 3808; 	(3) Products put up as charges for fire-extinguishers or put up in fire-extinguishing grenades (heading 3813); 	(4) Certified reference materials specified in note 2 below; 	(5) Products specified in note 3(a) or 3(c) below. (b) Mixtures of chemicals with foodstuffs or other substances with nutritive value, of a kind used in the preparation of human 	foodstuffs (generally, heading 2106); (c) Slag, ash and residues (including sludges, other than sewage sludge), containing metals, arsenic or their mixtures and 	meeting the requirements of note 3(a) or 3(b) to chapter 26 (heading 2620); (d) Medicaments (heading 3003 or 3004); or (e) Spent catalysts of a kind used for the extraction of base metals or for the manufacture of chemical compounds of base metals 	(heading 2620), spent catalysts of a kind used principally for the recovery of precious metal (heading 7112) or catalysts 	consisting of metals or metal alloys in the form of, for example, finely divided powder or woven gauze (section XIV or XV). 2. (a) For the purposes of heading 3822, the expression "certified reference materials" means reference materials which are 	accompanied by a certificate which indicates the values of the certified properties, the methods used to determine these 	values and the degree of certainty associated with each value and which are suitable for analytical, calibrating or referencing 	purposes. (b) With the exception of the products of chapter 28 or 29, for the classification of certified reference materials, heading 3822 	shall take precedence over any other heading in the tariff schedule. 3. Heading 3824 includes the following goods which are not to be classified in any other heading of the tariff schedule: (a) Cultured crystals (other than optical elements) weighing not less than 2.5 g each, of magnesium oxide or of the halides of 	the alkali or alkaline-earth metals; (b) Fusel oil; Dippel's oil; (c) Ink removers put up in packings for retail sale; (d) Stencil correctors, other correcting fluids and correction tapes (other than those of heading 9612), put up inpackings for retail 	sale; and (e) Ceramic firing testers, fusible (for example, Seger cones). 4. Throughout the tariff schedule, "municipal waste" means waste of a kind collected from households, hotels, restaurants, hospitals, 	shops, offices, etc., road and pavement sweepings, as well as construction and demolition waste. Municipal waste generally 	contains a large variety of materials such as plastics, rubber, wood, paper, textiles, glass, metals, food materials, broken furniture 	and other damaged or discarded articles. The term "municipal waste," does not cover: (a) Individual materials or articles segregated from the waste, such as wastes of plastics, rubber, wood, paper, textiles, glass 	or metals and spent batteries, which fall in their appropriate headings of the tariff schedule; (b) Industrial waste: (c) Waste pharmaceuticals, as defined in note 4(k) to chapter 30; or (d) Clinical waste, as defined in note 6(a), below. 5. For the purposes of heading 3825, "sewage sludge" means sludge arising from urban effluent treatment plants and includes 	pre-treatment waste, scourings and unstabilized sludge. Stabilized sludge, when suitable for use as fertilizer, is excluded (chapter 	31). 6. For the purposes of heading 3825, the expression "other wastes" applies to: (a) Clinical waste, that is, contaminated waste arising from medical research, diagnosis, treatment or other medical, surgical, 	dental or veterinary procedures, which often contain pathogens and pharmaceutical substances and require special disposal 	procedures (for example, soiled dressings, used gloves and used syringes); (b) Waste organic solvents; (c) Wastes of metal pickling liquors, hydraulic fluids, brake fluids and anti-freezing fluids; and (d) Other wastes from chemical or allied industries. 	The expression "other wastes" does not, however, cover wastes which contain mainly petroleum oils or oils obtained from 	bituminous materials (heading 2710). 7. For the purposes of heading 3826, the term "biodiesel" means mono-alkyl esters of fatty acids of a kind used as a fuel, derived 	from animal or vegetable fats and oils, whether or not used.  Subheading Notes 1. Subheading 3808.50 covers only goods of heading 3808, containing one or more of the following substances: aldrin (ISO); 	binapacryl (ISO); camphechlor (ISO) (toxaphene); captafol (ISO); chlordane (ISO); chlordimeform (ISO); chlorobenzilate (ISO); 	DDT (ISO) (clofenotane (INN), 1,1,1-trichloro-2,2-bis(p-chlorophenyl)ethane); dieldrin (ISO, INN); 4,6-dinitro-o-cresol (DNOC 	(ISO)) or its salts; dinoseb (ISO), its salts or its esters; ethylene dibromide (ISO) (1,2-dibromoethane); ethylene dichloride (ISO) 	(1,2-dichloroethane); fluoroacetamide (ISO); heptachlor (ISO); hexachlorobenzene (ISO); 1,2,3,4,5,6-hexachlorocyclohexane 	(HCH (ISO)), including lindane (ISO, INN); mercury compounds; methamidophos (ISO); monocrotophos (ISO); oxirane (ethylene 	oxide); parathion (ISO); parathion-methyl (ISO) (methylparathion); pentachlorophenol (ISO), its salts or its esters; phosphamidon 	(ISO); 2,4,5-T (ISO) (2,4,5-trichlorophenoxyacetic acid), its salts or its esters; tributyltin compounds. 	Subheading 3808.50 also covers dustable powder formulations containing a mixture of benomyl (ISO), carbofuran (ISO) and 	thiram (ISO). 2. For the purposes of subheadings 3825.41 and 3825.49, "waste organic solvents" are wastes containing mainly organic solvents, 	not fit for further use as presented as primary products, whether or not intended for recovery of the solvents.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN39</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN39</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. Throughout the tariff schedule the expression "plastics" means those materials of headings 3901 to 3914 which are or have been 	capable, either at the moment of polymerization or at some subsequent stage, of being formed under external influence (usually 	heat and pressure, if necessary with a solvent or plasticizer) by molding, casting, extruding, rolling or other process into shapes 	which are retained on the removal of the external influence. 	Throughout the tariff schedule, any reference to "plastics" also includes vulcanized fiber. The expression, however, does not 	apply to materials regarded as textile materials of section XI. 2. This chapter does not cover: (a) Lubricating preparations of 2710 or 3403; (b) Waxes of heading 2712 or 3404; (c) Separate chemically defined organic compounds (chapter 29); (d) Heparin or its salts (heading 3001); (e) Solutions (other than collodions) consisting of any of the products specified in headings 3901 to 3913 in volatile organic 	solvents when the weight of the solvent exceeds 50 percent of the weight of the solution (heading 3208); stamping foils of 	heading 3212; (f) Organic surface-active agents or preparations of heading 3402; (g) Run gums or ester gums (heading 3806); (h) Prepared additives for mineral oils (including gasoline) or for other liquids used for the same purposes as mineral oil (heading 	3811); (ij) Prepared hydraulic fluids based on polyglycols, silicones or other polymers of Chapter 39 (heading 3819); (k) Diagnostic or laboratory reagents on a backing of plastics (heading 3822); (l) Synthetic rubber, as defined for the purposes of chapter 40, or articles thereof; (m) Saddlery or harness (heading 4201) or trunks, suitcases, handbags or other containers of heading 4202; (n) Plaits, wickerwork or other articles of chapter 46; (o) Wall coverings of heading 4814; (P) Goods of section XI (textiles and textile articles); (q) Articles of section XII (for example, footwear, headgear, umbrellas, sun umbrellas, walking-sticks, whips, riding-crops or 	parts thereof); (r) Imitation jewelry of heading 7117; (s) Articles of section XVI (machines and mechanical or electrical appliances); (t) Parts of aircraft or vehicles of section XVII; (u) Articles of chapter 90 (for example, optical elements, spectacle frames, drawing instruments); (v) Articles of chapter 91 (for example, clock or watch cases); (w) Articles of chapter 92 (for example, musical instruments or parts thereof); (x) Articles of chapter 94 (for example, furniture, lamps and lighting fittings, illuminated signs, prefabricated buildings); (y) Articles of chapter 95 (for example, toys, games, sports equipment); or (z) Articles of chapter 96 (for example, brushes, buttons, slide fasteners, combs, mouthpieces or stems for smoking pipes, 	cigarette holders or the like, parts of vacuum flasks or the like, pens, mechanical pencils). 3. Headings 3901 to 3911 apply only to goods of a kind produced by chemical synthesis, falling in the following categories: (a) Liquid synthetic polyolefins of which less than 60 percent by volume distills at 300°C, after conversion to 1,013 millibars 	when a reduced-pressure distillation method is used (headings 3901 and 3902); (b) Resins, not highly polymerized, of the coumarone-indene type (heading 3911); (c) Other synthetic polymers with an average of at least five monomer units; (d) Silicones (heading 3910); (e) Resols (heading 3909) and other prepolymers. 4. The expression "copolymers" covers all polymers in which no single monomer contributes 95 percent or more by weight to the 	total polymer content. 	For the purposes of this chapter, except where the context otherwise requires, copolymers (including co-polycondensates, 	co-polyaddition products, block copolymers and graft copolymers) and polymer blends are to be classified in the heading covering 	polymers of that comonomer unit which predominates by weight over every other single comonomer unit. For the purposes of 	this note, constituent comonomer units of polymers falling in the same heading shall be taken together. 	If no single comonomer predominates, copolymers or polymer blends, as the case may be, are to be classified in the heading 	which occurs last in numerical order among those which equally merit consideration. 5. Chemically modified polymers, that is, those in which only appendages to the main polymer chain have been changed by chemical 	reaction, are to be classified in the heading appropriate to the unmodified polymer. This provision does not apply to graft 	copolymers. 6. In headings 3901 to 3914, the expression "primary forms" applies only to the following forms: (a) Liquids and pastes, including dispersions (emulsions and suspensions) and solutions; (b) Blocks of irregular shape, lumps, powders (including molding powders), granules, flakes and similar bulk forms. 7. Heading 3915 does not apply to waste, parings and scrap of a single thermoplastic material, transformed into primary forms 	(headings 3901 to 3914). 8. For the purposes of heading 3917, the expression "tubes, pipes and hoses" means hollow products, whether semimanufactures 	or finished products, of a kind generally used for conveying, conducting or distributing gases or liquids (for example, ribbed 	garden hose, perforated tubes). This expression also includes sausage casings and other lay-flat tubing. However, except for 	the last mentioned, those having an internal cross section other than round, oval, rectangular (in which the length does not 	exceed 1.5 times the width) or in the shape of a regular polygon are not to be regarded as tubes, pipes and hoses, but as profile 	shapes. 9. For the purposes of heading 3918, the expression "wall or ceiling coverings of plastics" applies to products in rolls, of a width 	not less than 45 cm, suitable for wall or ceiling decoration, consisting of plastics fixed permanently on a backing of any material 	other than paper, the layer of plastics (on the face side) being grained, embossed, colored, design-printed or otherwise decorated. 10. In headings 3920 and 3921, the expression "plates, sheets, film, foil and strip" applies only to plates, sheets, film, foil and strip 	(other than those of chapter 54) and to blocks of regular geometric shape, whether or not printed or otherwise surface-worked, 	uncut or cut into rectangles (including squares) but not further worked (even if when so cut they become articles ready for use). 11. Heading 3925 applies only to the following articles, not being products covered by any of the earlier headings of subchapter II: (a) Reservoirs, tanks (including septic tanks), vats and similar containers, of a capacity exceeding 300 liters; (b) Structural elements used, for example, in floors, walls or partitions, ceilings or roofs; (c) Gutters and fittings therefor; (d) Doors, windows and their frames and thresholds for doors; (e) Balconies, balustrades, fencing, gates and similar barriers; (f) Shutters, blinds (including venetian blinds) and similar articles and parts and fittings thereof; (g) Large-scale shelving for assembly and permanent installation, for example, in shops, workshops, warehouses; (h) Ornamental architectural features, for example, flutings, cupolas, dovecotes; and (ij) Fittings and mountings intended for permanent installation in or on doors, windows, staircases, walls or other parts of 	buildings, for example, knobs, handles, hooks, brackets, towel rails, switch plates and other protective plates.  Subheading Notes 1. Within any one heading of this chapter, polymers (including copolymers) are to be classified according to the following provisions: (a) Where there is a subheading named "Other" in the sam
e series: 	(1) The designation in a subheading of a polymer by the prefix "poly" (for example, polyethylene and polyamide-6,6) means 		that the constituent monomer unit or monomer units of the named polymer taken together must contribute 95 percent 		or more by weight of the total polymer content. 	(2) The copolymers named in subheadings 3901.30, 3903.20, 3903.30 and 3904.30 are to be classified in those subheadings, 		provided that the comonomer units of the named copolymers contribute 95 percent or more by weight of the total polymer 		content. 	(3) Chemically modified polymers are to be classified in the subheading named "Other", provided that the chemically modified 		polymers are not more specifically covered by another subheading. 	(4) Polymers not meeting (1), (2), or (3), above, are to be classified in the subheading, among the remaining subheadings 		in the series, covering polymers of that monomer unit which predominates by weight over every other single comonomer 		unit. For this purpose, constituent monomer units of polymers falling in the same subheading shall be taken together. 		Only the constituent comonomer units of the polymers in the series of subheadings under consideration are to be 		compared. (b) Where there is no subheading named "Other" in the same series: 	(1) Polymers are to be classified in the subheading covering polymers of that monomer unit which predominates by weight 		over every other single comonomer unit. For this purpose, constituent monomer units of polymers falling in the same 		subheading shall be taken together. Only the constituent comonomer units of the polymers in the series under 		consideration are to be compared. 	(2) Chemically modified polymers are to be classified in the subheading appropriate to the unmodified polymer. 		Polymer blends are to be classified in the same subheading as polymers of the same monomer units in the same proportions. 2. For the purposes of subheading 3920.43, the term “plasticizers” includes secondary plasticizers.</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN40</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN40</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. Except where the context otherwise requires, throughout the tariff schedule the expression "rubber" means the following products, 	whether or not vulcanized or hard: natural rubber, balata, gutta-percha, guayule, chicle and similar natural gums, synthetic rubber, 	factice derived from oils and such substances reclaimed. 2. This chapter does not cover: (a) Goods of section XI (textiles and textile articles); (b) Footwear or parts thereof of chapter 64; (c) Headgear or parts thereof (including bathing caps) of chapter 65; (d) Mechanical or electrical appliances or parts thereof of section XVI (including electrical goods of all kinds), of hard rubber; (e) Articles of chapter 90, 92, 94 or 96; or (f) Articles of chapter 95 (other than sports gloves, mittens and mitts and articles of headings 4011 to 4013). 3. In headings 4001 to 4003 and 4005, the expression "primary forms" applies only to the following forms : (a) Liquids and pastes (including latex, whether or not prevulcanized, and other dispersions and solutions); (b) Blocks of irregular shape, lumps, bales, powders, granules, crumbs and similar bulk forms. 4. In note 1 to this chapter and in heading 4002, the expression "synthetic rubber" applies to: (a) Unsaturated synthetic substances which can be irreversibly transformed by vulcanization with sulfur into non-thermoplastic 	substances which, at a temperature between 18°C and 29°C, will not break on being extended to three times their original 	length and will return, after being extended to twice their original length, within a period of 5 minutes, to a length not greater 	than 1-1/2 times their original length. For the purposes of this test, substances necessary for the cross-linking, such as 	vulcanizing activators or accelerators, may be added; the presence of substances as provided for by note 5(b)(ii) and (iii) is 	also permitted. However, the presence of any substances not necessary for the cross-linking, such as extenders, plasticizers 	and fillers, is not permitted; (b) Thioplasts (TM); and (c) Natural rubber modified by grafting or mixing with plastics, depolymerized natural rubber, mixtures of unsaturated synthetic 	substances with saturated synthetic high polymers provided that all the above-mentioned products comply with the requirements 	concerning vulcanization, elongation and recovery in (a) above. 5. (a) Headings 4001 and 4002 do not apply to any rubber or mixture of rubbers which has been compounded, before or after 		coagulation, with: 	(i) Vulcanizing agents, accelerators, retarders or activators (other than those added for the preparation of prevulcanized 		rubber latex); 	(ii) Pigments or other coloring matter other than those added solely for the purpose of identification; 	(iii) Pasticizers or extenders (except mineral oil in the case of oil-extended rubber), fillers, reinforcing agents, organic solvents 		or any other substances, except those permitted under (b); (b) The presence of the following substances in any rubber or mixture of rubbers shall not affect its classification in heading 	4001 or 4002, as the case may be, provided that such rubber or mixture of rubbers retains its essential character as a raw 	material: 	(i) Emulsifiers or antitack agents; 	(ii) Small amounts of breakdown products of emulsifiers; 	(iii) Very small amounts of the following: heat-sensitive agents (generally for obtaining thermosensitive rubber latexes), 		cationic surface-active agents (generally for obtaining electro-positive rubber latexes), antioxidants, coagulants, crumbling 		agents, freeze-resisting agents, peptizers, preservatives, stabilizers, viscosity-control agents or similar special-purpose 		additives. 6. For the purposes of heading 4004 the expression "waste, parings and scrap" means rubber waste, parings and scrap from the 	manufacture or working of rubber and rubber goods definitely not usable as such because of cutting-up, wear or other reasons. 7. Thread wholly of vulcanized rubber, of which any cross-sectional dimension exceeds 5 mm, is to be classified as strip, rods or 	profile shapes, of heading 4008. 8. Heading 4010 includes conveyor or transmission belts or belting of textile fabric impregnated, coated, covered or laminated with 	rubber or made from textile yarn or cord impregnated, coated, covered or sheathed with rubber. 9. In headings 4001, 4002, 4003, 4005 and 4008, the expressions "plates", "sheets" and "strip" apply only to plates, sheets and 	strip, and to blocks of regular geometric shape, uncut or simply cut to rectangular (including square) shape, whether or not having 	the character of articles and whether or not printed or otherwise surface-worked, but not otherwise cut to shape or further worked. 	In heading 4008 the expressions "rods" and "profile shapes" apply only to such products, whether or not cut to length or 	surface-worked but not otherwise worked.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN41</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN41</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Parings or similar waste, of raw hides or skins (heading 0511); (b) Birdskins or parts of birdskins, with their feathers or down, of heading 0505 or 6701; or (c) Hides or skins, with the hair or wool on, raw, tanned or dressed (chapter 43); the following are, however, to be classified in 	chapter 41, namely, raw hides and skins with the hair or wool on, of bovine animals (including buffalo), of equine animals, 	of sheep or lambs (except Astrakhan, Broadtail, Caracul, Persian or similar lambs, Indian, Chinese, Mongolian or Tibetan 	lambs), of goats or kids (except Yemen, Mongolian or Tibetan goats and kids), of swine (including peccary), of chamois, of 	gazelle, of camels (including dromedaries), of reindeer, of elk, of deer, of roebucks or of dogs. 2. (a) Headings 4104 to 4106 do not cover hides and skins which have undergone a tanning (including pre-tanning) process which 	is reversible (headings 4101 to 4103, as the case may be). (b) For the purposes of headings 4104 to 4106, the term “crust” includes hides and skins that have been retanned, colored or 	fat-liquored (stuffed) prior to drying. 3. Throughout the tariff schedule the expression "composition leather" means only substances of the kind referred to in heading 	4115.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN42</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN42</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. For the purposes of this chapter, the term "leather" includes chamois (including combination chamois) leather, patent leather, 	patent laminated leather and metalized leather. 2. This chapter does not cover: (a) Sterile surgical catgut or similar sterile suture materials (heading 3006); (b) Articles of apparel or clothing accessories (except gloves, mittens and mitts), lined with furskin or artificial fur or to which 	furskin or artificial fur is attached on the outside, except as mere trimming (heading 4303 or 4304); (c) Made up articles of netting (heading 5608); (d) Articles of chapter 64; (e) Headgear or parts thereof of chapter 65; (f) Whips, riding-crops or other articles of heading 6602; (g) Cuff-links, bracelets or other imitation jewelry (heading 7117); (h) Fittings or trimmings for harness, such as stirrups, bits, horse brasses and buckles, separately entered (generally section 	XV); (ij) Strings, skins for drums or the like, or other parts of musical instruments (heading 9209); (k) Articles of chapter 94 (for example, furniture, lamps and lighting fittings); (l) Articles of chapter 95 (for example, toys, games, sports equipment); or (m) Buttons, press-fasteners, snap-fasteners, press-studs, button molds or other parts of these articles, button blanks, of heading 	9606. 3. (A) In addition to the provisions of note 2, above, heading 4202 does not cover: 	(a) Bags made of sheeting of plastics, whether or not printed, with handles, not designed for prolonged use (heading 3923); 	(b) Articles of plaiting materials (heading 4602). (B) Articles of headings 4202 and 4203 which have parts of precious metal or metal clad with precious metal, of natural or 	cultured pearls, of precious or semiprecious stones (natural, synthetic or reconstructed) remain classified in those headings 	even if such parts constitute more than minor fittings or minor ornamentation, provided that these parts do not give the articles 	their essential character. If, on the other hand, the parts give the articles their essential character, the articles are to be 	classified in chapter 71. 4. For the purposes of heading 4203, the expression "articles of apparel and clothing accessories" applies, inter alia, to gloves, 	mittens and mitts (including those for sport or for protection), aprons and other protective clothing, braces, belts, bandoliers and 	wrist straps, but excluding watch straps (heading 9113).
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN43</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN43</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. Throughout the tariff schedule references to "furskins", other than to raw furskins of heading 4301, apply to hides or skins of all 	animals which have been tanned or dressed with the hair or wool on. 2. This chapter does not cover: (a) Birdskins or parts of birdskins, with their feathers or down (heading 0505 or 6701); (b) Raw hides or skins, with the hair or wool on, of chapter 41 (see note 1(c) to that chapter); (c) Gloves, mittens and mitts consisting of leather and furskin or of leather and artificial fur (heading 4203); (d) Articles of chapter 64; (e) Headgear or parts thereof of chapter 65; or (f) Articles of chapter 95 (for example, toys, games, sports equipment). 3. Heading 4303 includes furskins and parts thereof, assembled with the addition of other materials, and furskins and parts thereof, 	sewn together in the form of garments or parts or accessories of garments or in the form of other articles. 4. Articles of apparel and clothing accessories (except those excluded by note 2) lined with furskin or artificial fur or to which furskin 	or artificial fur is attached on the outside except as mere trimming are to be classified in heading 4303 or 4304 as the case may 	be. 5. Throughout the tariff schedule the expression "artificial fur" means any imitation of furskin consisting of wool, hair or other fibers 	gummed or sewn on to leather, woven fabric or other materials, but does not include imitation furskins obtained by weaving or 	knitting (generally, heading 5801 or 6001).
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN44</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN44</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Wood, in chips, in shavings, crushed, ground or powdered, of a kind used primarily in perfumery, in pharmacy, or for 	insecticidal, fungicidal or similar purposes (heading 1211); (b) Bamboo or other materials of a woody nature of a kind used primarily for plaiting, in the rough, whether or not split, sawn 	lengthwise or cut to length (heading 1401); (c) Wood, in chips, in shavings, ground or powdered, of a kind used primarily in dyeing or in tanning (heading 1404); (d) Activated charcoal (heading 3802); (e) Articles of heading 4202; (f) Goods of chapter 46; (g) Footwear or parts thereof of chapter 64; (h) Goods of chapter 66 (for example, umbrellas and walking-sticks and parts thereof); (ij) Goods of heading 6808; (k) Imitation jewelry of heading 7117; (l) Goods of section XVI or section XVII (for example, machine parts, cases, covers, cabinets for machines and apparatus and 	wheelwrights' wares); (m) Goods of section XVIII (for example, clock cases and musical instruments and parts thereof); (n) Parts of firearms (heading 9305); (o) Articles of chapter 94 (for example, furniture, lamps and lighting fittings, prefabricated buildings); (p) Articles of chapter 95 (for example, toys, games, sports equipment); (q) Articles of chapter 96 (for example, smoking pipes and parts thereof, buttons, pencils) excluding bodies and handles, of 	wood, for articles of heading 9603; or (r) Articles of chapter 97 (for example, works of art). 2. In this chapter, the expression "densified wood" means wood which has been subjected to chemical or physical treatment (being, 	in the case of layers bonded together, treatment in excess of that needed to insure a good bond), and which has thereby acquired 	increased density or hardness together with improved mechanical strength or resistance to chemical or electrical agencies. 3. Headings 4414 to 4421 apply to articles of the respective descriptions of particle board or similar board, fiberboard, laminated 	wood or densified wood as they apply to such articles of wood. 4. Products of heading 4410, 4411 or 4412 may be worked to form the shapes provided for in respect of the articles of heading 	4409, curved, corrugated, perforated, cut or formed to shapes other than square or rectangular or submitted to any other operation 	provided it does not give them the character of articles of other headings. 5. Heading 4417 does not apply to tools in which the blade, working edge, working surface or other working part is formed by any 	of the materials specified in note 1 to chapter 82. 6. Subject to note 1 above and except where the context otherwise requires, any reference to "wood" in a heading of this chapter 	applies also to bamboo and other materials of a woody nature.  Subheading Notes 1. For the purposes of subheading 4401.31, the expression "wood pellets" means by-products such as cutter shavings, sawdust 	or chips, of the mechanical wood processing industry, furniture-making industry or other wood transformation activities, which 	have been agglomerated either directly by compression or by the addition of a binder in a proportion not exceeding 3 percent 	by weight. Such pellets are cylindrical, with a diameter not exceeding 25 mm and a length not exceeding 100 mm. 2. For the purposes of subheadings 4403.41 to 4403.49, 4407.21 to 4407.29, 4408.31 to 4408.39 and 4412.31, the expression 	“tropical wood” means one of the following types of wood : 	Abura, Acajou d'Afrique, Afrormosia, Ako, Alan, Andiroba, Aningré, Avodiré, Azobé, Balau, Balsa, Bossé clair, Bossé foncé, 	Cativo, Cedro, Dabema, Dark Red Meranti, Dibétou, Doussié, Framiré, Freijo, Fromager, Fuma, Geronggang, Ilomba, Imbuia, 	Ipé, Iroko, Jaboty, Jelutong, Jequitiba, Jongkong, Kapur, Kempas, Keruing, Kosipo, Kotibé, Koto, Light Red Meranti, Limba, 	Louro, MaÇaranduba, Mahogany, Makoré, Mandioqueira, Mansonia, Mengkulang, Meranti Bakau, Merawan, Merbau, 	Merpauh, Mersawa, Moabi, Niangon, Nyatoh, Obeche, Okoumé, Onzabili, Orey, Ovengkol, Ozigo, Padauk, Paldao, Palissandre 	de Guatemala, Palissandre de Para, Palissandre de Rio, Palissandre de Rose, Pau Amarelo, Pau Marfim, Pulai, Punah, 	Quaruba, Ramin, Sapelli, Saqui-Saqui, Sepetir, Sipo, Sucupira, Suren, Tauari, Teak, Tiama, Tola, Virola, White Lauan, 	White Meranti, White Seraya, Yellow Meranti.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN45</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN45</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Note 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Footwear or parts of footwear of chapter 64; (b) Headgear or parts of headgear of chapter 65; or (c) Articles of chapter 95 (for example, toys, games, sports equipment).
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN46</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN46</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. In this chapter the expression "plaiting materials" means materials in a state or form suitable for plaiting, interlacing or similar 	processes; it includes straw, osier or willow, bamboos, rattans, rushes, reeds, strips of wood, strips of other vegetable material 	(for example, strips of bark, narrow leaves and raffia or other strips obtained from broad leaves), unspun natural textile fibers, 	monofilament and strip and the like of plastics and strips of paper, but not strips of leather or composition leather or of felt or 	nonwovens, human hair, horsehair, textile rovings or yarns, or monofilament and strip and the like of chapter 54. 2. This chapter does not cover: (a) Wall coverings of heading 4814; (b) Twine, cordage, ropes or cables, plaited or not (heading 5607); (c) Footwear or headgear or parts thereof of chapter 64 or 65; (d) Vehicles or bodies for vehicles of basketware (chapter 87); or (e) Articles of chapter 94 (for example, furniture, lamps and lighting fittings). 3. For the purposes of heading 4601, the expression "plaiting materials, plaits and similar products of plaiting materials, bound 	together in parallel strands" means plaiting materials, plaits and similar products of plaiting materials, placed side by side and 	bound together, in the form of sheets, whether or not the binding materials are of spun textile materials.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN47</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN47</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Note 1. For the purposes of heading 4702, the expression "chemical wood pulp, dissolving grades" means chemical woodpulp having by weight an insoluble fraction of 92 percent or more for soda or sulfate woodpulp or of 88 percent or more for sulfite woodpulp after one hour in a caustic soda solution containing 18 percent sodium hydroxide (NaOH) at 20°C, and for sulfite woodpulp an ash content that does not exceed 0.15 percent by weight.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN48</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN48</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. For the purposes of this chapter, except where the context otherwise requires, a reference to "paper" includes references to 	paperboard (irrespective of thickness or weight per m2). 2. This chapter does not cover: (a) Articles of chapter 30; (b) Stamping foils of heading 3212; (c) Perfumed papers or papers impregnated or coated with cosmetics (chapter 33); (d) Paper or cellulose wadding impregnated, coated or covered with soap or detergent (heading 3401), or with polishes, creams 	or similar preparations (heading 3405); (e) Sensitized paper or paperboard of headings 3701 to 3704; (f) Paper impregnated with diagnostic or laboratory reagents (heading 3822); (g) Paper-reinforced stratified sheeting of plastics, or one layer of paper or paperboard coated or covered with a layer of plastics, 	the latter constituting more than half the total thickness, or articles of such materials, other than wallcoverings of heading 	4814 (chapter 39); (h) Articles of heading 4202 (for example, travel goods); (ij) Articles of chapter 46 (manufactures of plaiting material); (k) Paper yarn or textile articles of paper yarn (section XI); (l) Articles of chapter 64 or chapter 65; (m) Abrasive paper or paperboard (heading 6805) or paper- or paperboard-backed mica (heading 6814) (paper and paperboard 	coated with mica powder are, however, to be classified in this chapter); (n) Metal foil backed with paper or paperboard (generally section XIV or XV); (o) Articles of heading 9209; (p) Articles of chapter 95 (for example, toys, games, sports requisites); or (q) Articles of chapter 96 (for example, buttons, sanitary towels (pads) and tampons, napkins (diapers) and napkin liners for 	babies). 3. Subject to the provisions of note 7, headings 4801 to 4805 include paper and paperboard which have been subjected to 	calendering, super-calendering, glazing or similar finishing, false water-marking or surface sizing, and also paper, paperboard, 	cellulose wadding and webs of cellulose fibers, colored or marbled throughout the mass by any method. Except where heading 	4803 otherwise requires, these headings do not apply to paper, paperboard, cellulose wadding or webs of cellulose fibers which 	have been otherwise processed. 4. In this chapter, the expression "newsprint" means uncoated paper of a kind used for the printing of newspapers, of which not 	less than 50 percent by weight of the total fiber content consists of wood fibers obtained by a mechanical or chemi-mechanical 	process, unsized or very lightly sized, having a surface roughness Parker Print Surf (1 MPa) on each side exceeding 2.5 	micrometers (microns), weighing not less than 40 g/m2 and not more than 65 g/m2. 5. For the purposes of heading 4802, the expressions "paper and paperboard, of a kind used for writing, printing or other graphic 	purposes" and "nonperforated punch-cards and punch tape paper" mean paper and paperboard made mainly from bleached 	pulp or from pulp obtained by a mechanical or chemi-mechanical process and satisfying any of the following criteria: 	For paper or paperboard weighing not more than 150 g/m2: (a) Containing 10 percent or more of fibers obtained by a mechanical or chemi-mechanical process, and 	1. weighing not more than 80 g/m2, or 	2. colored throughout the mass; or (b) Containing more than 8 percent ash, and 	1. weighing not more than 80 g/m2, or 	2. colored throughout the mass; or (c) Containing more than 3 percent ash and having a brightness of 60 percent or more; or (d) Containing more than 3 percent but not more than 8 percent ash, having a brightness less than 60 percent and a burst index 	equal to or less than 2.5 kPa·m2/g; or (e) Containing 3 percent ash or less, having a brightness of 60 percent or more and a burst index equal to or less than 2.5 	kPa·m2/g. For paper or paperboard weighing more than 150 g/m2: (a) Colored throughout the mass; or (b) Having a brightness of 60 percent or more, and 	1. a caliper of 225 micrometers (microns) or less, or 	2. a caliper of more than 225 micrometers but not more than 508 micrometers (microns) and an ash content of more than 	3 percent; or (c) Having a brightness of less than 60 percent, a caliper of 254 micrometers (microns) or less and an ash content of more than 	8 percent. 	Heading 4802 does not, however, cover filter paper or paperboard (including teabag paper) or felt paper or paperboard. 6. In this chapter "kraft paper and paperboard" means paper and paperboard of which not less than 80 percent by weight of the 	total fiber content consists of fibers obtained by the chemical sulfate or soda processes. 7. Except where the terms of the headings otherwise require, paper, paperboard, cellulose wadding and webs of cellulose fibers 	answering to a description in two or more of the headings 4801 to 4811 are to be classified under that one of such headings 	which occurs last in numerical order in the tariff schedule. 8. Headings 4801 and 4803 to 4809 apply only to paper, paperboard, cellulose wadding and webs of cellulose fibers: (a) In strips or rolls of a width exceeding 36 cm; or (b) In rectangular (including square) sheets with one side exceeding 36 cm and the other side exceeding 15 cm in the unfolded 	state. 9. For the purposes of heading 4814, the expression "wallpaper and similar wall coverings" applies only to: (a) Paper in rolls, of a width of not less than 45 cm and not more than 160 cm, suitable for wall or ceiling decoration: 	(i) Grained, embossed, surface-colored, design-printed or otherwise surface-decorated (for example, with textile flock), 		whether or not coated or covered with transparent protective plastics; 	(ii) With an uneven surface resulting from the incorporation of particles of wood, straw, etc.; 	(iii) Coated or covered on the face side with plastics, the layer of plastics being grained, embossed, colored, design-printed 		or otherwise decorated; or 	(iv) Covered on the face side with plaiting material, whether or not bound together in parallel strands or woven; (b) Borders and friezes of paper, treated as above, whether or not in rolls, suitable for wall or ceiling decoration; (c) Wall coverings of paper made up of several panels, in rolls or sheets, printed so as to make up a scene, design or motif 	when applied to a wall. 	Products on a base of paper or paperboard, suitable for use both as floor coverings and as wall coverings, are to be classified 	in heading 4823. 10. Heading 4820 does not cover loose sheets or cards, cut to size, whether or not printed, embossed or perforated. 11. Heading 4823 applies, inter alia, to perforated paper or paperboard cards for Jacquard or similar machines and paper lace. 12. Except for the articles of heading 4814 or 4821, paper, paperboard, cellulose wadding and articles thereof, printed with motifs, 	characters or pictorial representations, which are not merely incidental to the primary use of the goods, fall in chapter 49.  Subheading Notes. For the purposes of subheading 4804.11 and 4804.19, "kraftliner" means machine-finished or machine-glazed paper and paperboard, of which not less than 80 percent by weight of the total fiber content consists of wood fibers obtained by the chemical sulfate or soda processes, in rolls, weighing more than 115 g/m2 and having a minimum Mullen bursting strength, as indicated in the following table, or the linearly interpolated or extrapolated equivalent for any other weight: ______________________________________________ Weight		Minimum Mullen bursting strength g/m²		KPa 115	 		393 125	 		417 200	 		637 300	 		824 400	 		961 ______________________________________________  2. For the purposes of subheadings 4804.21 and 4804.29, "sack kraft
paper" means machine-finished paper, of which not less 	than 80 percent by weight of the total fiber content consists of fibers obtained by the chemical sulfate or soda processes, in rolls, 	weighing not less than 60 g/m2 but not more than 115 g/m2 and meeting one of the following sets of specifications: 	(a) Having a Mullen burst index of not less than 3.7 kPa·m2/g and a stretch factor of more than 4.5 percent in the cross direction 		and of more than 2 percent in the machine direction. 	(b) Having minima for tear and tensile as indicated in the following table, or the linearly interpolated equivalent for any other 		weight: ________________________________________________________________________ Weight		Minimum tear mN					Minimum tensile kN/m g/m²		Machine		Machine				Cross		Machine 			direction	direction plus		direction	direction plus  						cross direction					cross direction ________________________________________________________________________	 60			700			1,510				1.9			6 70			830			1,790				2.3			7.2 80			965			2,070				2.8			8.3 100			1,230		2,635				3.7			10.6 115			1,425		3,060				4.4			12.3 ________________________________________________________________________  3. For the purposes of subheading 4805.11, "semichemical fluting paper" means paper, in rolls, of which not less than 65 percent 	by weight of the total fiber content consists of unbleached hardwood fibers obtained by a combination of mechanical and chemical 	pulping processes, and having a CMT 30 (Corrugated Medium Test with 30 minutes of conditioning) crush resistance exceeding 	1.8 newtons/g/m2 at 50 percent relative humidity, at 23°C. 4. Subheading 4805.12 covers paper, in rolls, made mainly of straw pulp obtained by a combination of mechanical and chemical 	pulping processes, weighing 130 g/m2 or more, and having a CMT 30 (Corrugated Medium Test with 30 minutes of conditioning) 	crush resistance exceeding 1.4 newtons/g/m2 at 50 percent relative humidity, at 23°C. 5. Subheading 4805.24 and 4805.25 cover paper and paperboard made wholly or mainly of pulp recovered (waste and scrap) 	paper or paperboard. Testliner may also have a surface layer of dyed paper or of paper made of bleached or unbleached 	non-recovered pulp. These products have a Mullen burst index of not less than 2 kPa·m2/g. 6. For the purposes of subheading 4805.30, "sulfite wrapping paper" means machine-glazed paper, of which more than 40 percent 	by weight of the total fiber content consists of wood fibers obtained by the chemical sulfite process, having an ash content not 	exceeding 8 percent and having a Mullen burst index of not less than 1.47 kPa·m2/g. 7. For the purposes of subheading 4810.22, "light-weight coated paper" means paper, coated on both sides, of a total weight not 	exceeding 72 g/m2, with a coating weight not exceeding 15 g/m2 per side, on a base of which not less than 50 percent by weight 	of the total fiber content consists of wood fibers obtained by a mechanical process.</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN49</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN49</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Photographic negatives or positives on transparent bases (chapter 37); (b) Maps, plans or globes, in relief, whether or not printed (heading 9023); (c) Playing cards or other goods of chapter 95; or (d) Original engravings, prints or lithographs (heading 9702), postage or revenue stamps, stamp-postmarks, first-day covers, 	postal stationery or the like of heading 9704, antiques of an age exceeding one hundred years or other articles of chapter 	97. 2. For the purposes of chapter 49 the term "printed" also means reproduced by means of a duplicating machine, produced under 	the control of an automatic data processing machine, embossed, photographed, photocopied, thermocopied or typewritten. 3. Newspapers, journals and periodicals which are bound otherwise than in paper, and sets of newspapers, journals or periodicals 	comprising more than one issue under a single cover are to be classified in heading 4901, whether or not containing advertising 	material. 4. Heading 4901 also covers: (a) A collection of printed reproductions of, for example, works of art or drawings, with a relative text, put up with numbered 	pages in a form suitable for binding into one or more volumes; (b) A pictorial supplement accompanying and subsidiary to, a bound volume; and (c) Printed parts of books or booklets, in the form of assembled or separate sheets or signatures, constituting the whole or a 	part of a complete work and designed for binding. 	However, printed pictures or illustrations not bearing a text, whether in the form of signatures or separate sheets, fall in heading 	4911. 5. Subject to note 3 of this chapter, heading 4901 does not cover publications which are essentially devoted to advertising (for 	example, brochures, pamphlets, leaflets, trade catalogs, yearbooks published by trade associations and tourist promotional 	literature). Such publications are to be classified in heading 4911. 6. For the purposes of heading 4903, the expression "children's picture books" means books for children in which the pictures form 	the principal interest and the text is subsidiary.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN51</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN51</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Note 1. Throughout the tariff schedule: (a) "Wool" means the natural fiber grown by sheep or lambs; (b) "Fine animal hair" means the hair of alpaca, llama, vicuna, camel (including dromedary), yak, Angora, Tibetan, Kashmir or 	similar goats (but not common goats), rabbit (including Angora rabbit), hare, beaver, nutria or muskrat; and (c) "Coarse animal hair" means the hair of animals not mentioned above, excluding brush-making hair and bristles (heading 	0502) and horsehair (heading 0511).
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN52</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN52</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Subheading Note 1. For the purposes of subheadings 5209.42 and 5211.42, the expression "denim" means fabrics of yarns of different colors, of 3-thread or 4-thread twill, including broken twill, warp faced, the warp yarns of which are of one and the same color and the weft 	yarns of which are unbleached, bleached, dyed grey or colored a lighter shade of the color of the warp yarns.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN54</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN54</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. Throughout the tariff schedule, the term "man-made fibers" means staple fibers and filaments of organic polymers produced by 	manufacturing processes, either: (a) By polymerization of organic monomers to produce polymers such as polyamides, polyesters, polyolefins or polyurethanes, 	or by chemical modification of polymers produced by this process (for example, poly(vinyl alcohol) prepared by the hydrolysis 	of poly(vinyl acetate)); or (b) By dissolution or chemical treatment of natural organic polymers (for example, cellulose) to produce polymers such as 	cuprammonium rayon (cupro) or viscose rayon, or by chemical modification of natural organic polymers (for example, 	cellulose, casein and other proteins, or alginic acid), to produce polymers such as cellulose acetate or alginates. 	The terms "synthetic" and "artificial", used in relation to fibers, mean: synthetic: fibers as defined at (a); artificial: fibers as defined 	at (b). Strip and the like of heading 5404 or 5405 are not considered to be man-made fibers. 	The terms "man-made", "synthetic" and "artificial" shall have the same meanings when used in relation to "textile materials". 2. Headings 5402 and 5403 do not apply to synthetic or artificial filament tow of chapter 55.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN55</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN55</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Note 1. Headings 5501 and 5502 apply only to man-made filament tow, consisting of parallel filaments of a uniform length equal to the 	length of the tow, meeting the following specifications: (a) Length of tow exceeding 2 m; (b) Twist less than 5 turns per meter; (c) Measuring per filament less than 67 decitex; (d) Synthetic filament tow only: the tow must be drawn, that is to say, be incapable of being stretched by more than 100 percent 	of its length; and (e) Total measurement of tow more than 20,000 decitex. 	Tow of a length not exceeding 2 m is to be classified in heading 5503 or 5504.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN56</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN56</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Wadding, felt or nonwovens, impregnated, coated or covered with substances or preparations (for example, perfumes or 	cosmetics of chapter 33, soaps or detergents of heading 3401, polishes, creams or similar preparations of heading 3405, 	fabric softeners of heading 3809) where the textile material is present merely as a carrying medium; (b) Textile products of heading 5811; (c) Natural or artificial abrasive powder or grain, on a backing of felt or nonwovens (heading 6805); (d) Agglomerated or reconstituted mica, on a backing of felt or nonwovens (heading 6814); (e) Metal foil on a backing of felt or nonwovens (generally section XIV or XV); or (f) Sanitary towels (pads) and tampons, napkins and napkin liners for babies and similar articles of heading 9619. 2. The term "felt" includes needleloom felt and fabrics consisting of a web of textile fibers the cohesion of which has been enhanced 	by a stitch-bonding process using fibers from the web itself. 3. Headings 5602 and 5603 cover respectively felt and nonwovens, impregnated, coated, covered or laminated with plastics or 	rubber whatever the nature of these materials (compact or cellular). 	Heading 5603 also includes nonwovens in which plastics or rubber forms the bonding substance. 	Headings 5602 and 5603 do not, however, cover: (a) Felt impregnated, coated, covered or laminated with plastics or rubber, containing 50 percent or less by weight of textile 	material or felt completely embedded in plastics or rubber (chapter 39 or 40); (b) Nonwovens, either completely embedded in plastics or rubber, or entirely coated or covered on both sides with such materials, 	provided that such coating or covering can be seen with the naked eye with no account being taken of any resulting change 	of color (chapter 39 or 40); or (c) Plates, sheets or strip of cellular plastics or cellular rubber combined with felt or nonwovens, where the textile material is 	present merely for reinforcing purposes (chapter 39 or 40). 4. Heading 5604 does not cover textile yarn, or strip or the like of heading 5404 or 5405, in which the impregnation, coating or 	covering cannot be seen with the naked eye (usually chapters 50 to 55); for the purpose of this provision, no account should be 	taken of any resulting change of color.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN57</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN57</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. For the purposes of this chapter, the term "carpets and other textile floor coverings" means floor coverings in which textile 	materials serve as the exposed surface of the article when in use and includes articles having the characteristics of textile floor 	coverings but intended for use for other purposes. 2. This chapter does not cover floor covering underlays.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN58</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN58</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not apply to textile fabrics referred to in note 1 to chapter 59, impregnated, coated, covered or laminated, or 	to other goods of chapter 59. 2. Heading 5801 also includes woven weft pile fabrics which have not yet had the floats cut, at which stage they have no pile 	standing up. 3. For the purposes of heading 5803, "gauze" means a fabric with a warp composed wholly or in part of standing or ground threads 	and crossing or doup threads which cross the standing or ground threads making a half turn, a complete turn or more to form 	loops through which weft threads pass. 4. Heading 5804 does not apply to knotted net fabrics of twine, cordage or rope, of heading 5608. 5. For the purposes of heading 5806, the expression "narrow woven fabrics" means: (a) Woven fabrics of a width not exceeding 30 cm, whether woven as such or cut from wider pieces, provided with selvages 	(woven, gummed or otherwise made) on both edges; (b) Tubular woven fabrics of a flattened width not exceeding 30 cm; and (c) Bias binding with folded edges, of a width when unfolded not exceeding 30 cm. 	Narrow woven fabrics with woven fringes are to be classified in heading 5808. 6. In heading 5810, the expression "embroidery" means, inter alia , embroidery with metal or glass thread on a visible ground of 	textile fabric, and sewn applique work of sequins, beads or ornamental motifs of textile or other materials. The heading does not 	apply to needlework tapestry (heading 5805). 7. In addition to the products of heading 5809, this chapter also includes articles made of metal thread and of a kind used in apparel, 	as furnishing fabrics or for similar purposes.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN59</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN59</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. Except where the context otherwise requires, for the purposes of this chapter the expression "textile fabrics" applies only to the 	woven fabrics of chapters 50 to 55 and headings 5803 and 5806, the braids and ornamental trimmings in the piece of heading 	5808 and the knitted or crocheted fabrics of headings 6002 to 6006. 2. Heading 5903 applies to: (a) Textile fabrics, impregnated, coated, covered or laminated with plastics, whatever the weight per square meter and whatever 	the nature of the plastic material (compact or cellular), other than: 	(1) Fabrics in which the impregnation, coating or covering cannot be seen with the naked eye (usually chapters 50 to 55, 		58 or 60); for the purpose of this provision, no account should be taken of any resulting change of color; 	(2) Products which cannot, without fracturing, be bent manually around a cylinder of a diameter of 7 mm, at a temperature 		between 15°C and 30°C (usually chapter 39); 	(3) Products in which the textile fabric is either completely embedded in plastics or entirely coated or covered on both sides 		with such material, provided that such coating or covering can be seen with the naked eye with no account being taken 		of any resulting change of color (chapter 39); 	(4) Fabrics partially coated or partially covered with plastics and bearing designs resulting from these treatments (usually 		chapters 50 to 55, 58 or 60); 	(5) Plates, sheets or strip of cellular plastics, combined with textile fabric, where the textile fabric is present merely for 		reinforcing purposes (chapter 39); or 	(6) Textile products of heading 5811. (b) Fabrics made from yarn, strip or the like, impregnated, coated, covered or sheathed with plastics, of heading 5604. 3. For the purposes of heading 5905, the expression "textile wall coverings" applies to products in rolls, of a width of not less than 	45 cm, suitable for wall or ceiling decoration, consisting of a textile surface which has been fixed on a backing or has been treated 	on the back (impregnated or coated to permit pasting). 	This heading does not, however, apply to wall coverings consisting of textile flock or dust fixed directly on a backing of paper 	(heading 4814) or on a textile backing (generally heading 5907). 4. For the purposes of heading 5906, the expression "rubberized textile fabrics" means: (a) Textile fabrics impregnated, coated, covered or laminated with rubber: 	(i) Weighing not more than 1,500 g/m2; or 	(ii) Weighing more than 1,500 g/m2 and containing more than 50 percent by weight of textile material; (b) Fabrics made from yarn, strip or the like, impregnated, coated, covered or sheathed with rubber, of heading 5604; and (c) Fabrics composed of parallel textile yarns agglomerated with rubber, irrespective of their weight per square meter. 	This heading does not, however, apply to plates, sheets or strip of cellular rubber, combined with textile fabric, where the textile 	fabric is present merely for reinforcing purposes (chapter 40), or textile products of heading 5811. 5. Heading 5907 does not apply to: (a) Fabrics in which the impregnation, coating or covering cannot be seen with the naked eye (usually chapters 50 to 55, 58 or 	60); for the purpose of this provision, no account should be taken of any resulting change of color; (b) Fabrics painted with designs (other than painted canvas being theatrical scenery, studio back-cloths or the like); (c) Fabrics partially covered with flock, dust, powdered cork or the like and bearing designs resulting from these treatments; 	however, imitation pile fabrics remain classified in this heading; (d) Fabrics finished with normal dressings having a basis of amylaceous or similar substances; (e) Wood veneered on a backing of textile fabrics (heading 4408); (f) Natural or artificial abrasive powder or grain, on a backing of textile fabrics (heading 6805); (g) Agglomerated or reconstituted mica, on a backing of textile fabrics (heading 6814); or (h) Metal foil on a backing of textile fabrics (generally Section XIV or XV). 6. Heading 5910 does not apply to: (a) Transmission or conveyor belting, of textile material, of a thickness of less than 3 mm; or (b) Transmission or conveyor belts or belting of textile fabric impregnated, coated, covered or laminated with rubber or made 	from textile yarn or cord impregnated, coated, covered or sheathed with rubber (heading 4010). 7. Heading 5911 applies to the following goods, which do not fall in any other heading of section XI: (a) Textile products in the piece, cut to length or simply cut to rectangular (including square) shape (other than those having the 	character of the products of headings 5908 to 5910), the following only: 	(i) Textile fabrics, felt and felt-lined woven fabrics, coated, covered or laminated with rubber, leather or other material, of 	a kind used for card clothing, and similar fabrics of a kind used for other technical purposes, including narrow fabrics 	made of velvet impregnated with rubber, for covering weaving spindles (weaving beams); 	(ii) Bolting cloth; 	(iii) Straining cloth of a kind used in oil presses or the like, of textile material or of human hair; 	(iv) Flat woven textile fabrics with multiple warp or weft, whether or not felted, impregnated or coated, of a kind used in 	machinery or for other technical purposes; 	(v) Textile fabric reinforced with metal, of a kind used for technical purposes; 	(vi) Cords, braids and the like, whether or not coated, impregnated or reinforced with metal, of a kind used in industry as 	packing or lubricating materials; (b) Textile articles (other than those of headings 5908 to 5910) of a kind used for technical purposes (for example, textile fabrics 	and felts, endless or fitted with linking devices, of a kind used in papermaking or similar machines (for example, for pulp or 	asbestos-cement), gaskets, washers, polishing discs and other machinery parts).
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN60</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN60</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Crochet lace of heading 5804; (b) Labels, badges or similar articles, knitted or crocheted, of heading 5807; or (c) Knitted or crocheted fabrics, impregnated, coated, covered or laminated, of chapter 59. However, knitted or crocheted pile 	fabrics, impregnated, coated, covered or laminated, remain classified in heading 6001. 2. This chapter also includes fabrics made of metal thread and of a kind used in apparel, as furnishing fabrics or for similar purposes. 3. Throughout the tariff schedule any reference to "knitted" goods includes a reference to stitch-bonded goods in which the chain 	stitches are formed of textile yarn.       Subheading Note      1. Subheading 6005.35 covers fabrics of polyethylene monofilament or of polyester multifilament, weighing not less than 30g/m2 and  not more than 55 g/m2, having a mesh size of not less than 20 holes/cm2 and not more than 100 holes/cm2, and impregnated or coated with alpha-cypermethrin (ISO), chlorfenapyr (ISO), deltamethrin (INN, ISO), lambda-cyhalothrin (ISO), permethrin (ISO), or pirimiphos-methyl (ISO).
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN61</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN61</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter applies only to made up knitted or crocheted articles. 2. This chapter does not cover: (a) Goods of heading 6212; (b) Worn clothing or other worn articles of heading 6309; (c) Orthopedic appliances, surgical belts, trusses or the like (heading 9021). 3. For the purposes of headings 6103 and 6104: (a) The term "suit" means a set of garments composed of two or three pieces made up, in respect of their outer surface, in 	identical fabric and comprising: 	- one suit coat or jacket the outer shell of which, exclusive of sleeves, consists of four or more panels, designed to cover 		the upper part of the body, possibly with a tailored waistcoat in addition whose front is made from the same fabric as 		the outer surface of the other components of the set and whose back is made from the same fabric as the lining of the 		suit coat or jacket; and 	- one garment designed to cover the lower part of the body and consisting of trousers, breeches or shorts (other than 		swim- wear), a skirt or a divided skirt, having neither braces nor bibs. 	All of the components of a "suit" must be of the same fabric construction, color and composition; they must also be of the 	same style and of corresponding or compatible size. However, these components may have piping (a strip of fabric sewn 	into the seam) in a different fabric. 	If several separate components to cover the lower part of the body are presented together (for example, two pairs of trousers 	or trousers and shorts, or a skirt or divided skirt and trousers), the constituent lower part shall be one pair of trousers or, in 	the case of women's or girls' suits, the skirt or divided skirt, the other garments being considered separately. 	The term "suit" includes the following sets of garments whether or not they fulfill all the above conditions: 	- morning dress, comprising a plain jacket (cutaway) with rounded tails hanging well down at the back and striped trousers; 	- evening dress (tailcoat), generally made of black fabric, the jacket of which is relatively short at the front, does not close 		and has narrow skirts cut in at the hips and hanging down behind; 	- dinner jacket suits, in which the jacket is similar in style to an ordinary jacket (though perhaps revealing more of the shirt 		front), but has shiny silk or imitation silk lapels. (b) The term "ensemble" means a set of garments (other than suits and articles of heading 6107, 6108 or 6109), composed of 	several pieces made up in identical fabric, put up for retail sale, and comprising: 	- one garment designed to cover the upper part of the body, with the exception of pullovers which may form a second 		upper garment in the sole context of twin sets, and of waistcoats which may also form a second upper garment, and 	- one or two different garments, designed to cover the lower part of the body and consisting of trousers, bib and brace 		overalls, breeches, shorts (other than swimwear), a skirt or a divided skirt. 	All of the components of an ensemble must be of the same fabric construction, style, color and composition; they also must 	be of corresponding or compatible size. The term "ensemble" does not apply to track suits or ski-suits of heading 6112. 4. Headings 6105 and 6106 do not cover garments with pockets below the waist, with a ribbed waistband or other means of tightening 	at the bottom of the garment, or garments having an average of less than 10 stitches per linear centimeter in each direction 	counted on an area measuring at least 10 centimeters by 10 centimeters. Heading 6105 does not cover sleeveless garments. 5. Heading 6109 does not cover garments with a drawstring, ribbed waistband or other means of tightening at the bottom of the 	garment. 6. For the purposes of heading 6111: (a) The expression "babies' garments and clothing accessories" means articles for young children of a body height not exceeding 	86 centimeters; (b) Articles which are, prima facie, classifiable both in heading 6111 and in other headings of this chapter are to be classified 	in heading 6111. 7. For the purposes of heading 6112, "ski-suits", means garments or sets of garments which, by their general appearance and 	texture, are identifiable as intended to be worn principally for skiing (cross-country or alpine). They consist either of: (a) A "ski overall," that is, a one-piece garment designed to cover the upper and the lower parts of the body; in addition to sleeves 	and a collar the ski overall may have pockets or footstraps; or (b) A "ski ensemble," that is, a set of garments composed of two or three pieces, put up for retail sale and comprising: 	- one garment such as an anorak, windbreaker or similar article, closed by a slide fastener (zipper), possibly with a 		waistcoat in addition, and 	- one pair of trousers whether or not extending above waist level, one pair of breeches or one bib and brace overall. 		The "ski ensemble" may also consist of an overall similar to the one mentioned in paragraph (a) above and a type of padded, 		sleeveless jacket worn over the overall. 	All the components of a "ski ensemble" must be made up in a fabric of the same texture, style and composition whether or 	not of the same color; they also must be of corresponding or compatible size. 8. Garments which are, prima facie, classifiable both in heading 6113 and in other headings of this chapter, excluding heading 	6111, are to be classified in heading 6113. 9. Garments of this chapter designed for left over right closure at the front shall be regarded as men's or boys' garments, and those 	designed for right over left closure at the front as women's or girls' garments. These provisions do not applywhere the cut of the 	garment clearly indicates that it is designed for one or other of the sexes. 	Garments which cannot be identified as either men's or boys' garments or as women's or girls' garments are to be classified in 	the headings covering women's or girls' garments. 10. Articles of this chapter may be made of metal thread.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN62</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN62</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter applies only to made up articles of any textile fabric other than wadding, excluding knitted or crocheted articles 	(other than those of heading 6212). 2. This chapter does not cover: (a) Worn clothing or other worn articles of heading 6309; (b) Orthopedic appliances, surgical belts, trusses or the like (heading 9021). 3. For the purposes of headings 6203 and 6204: (a) The term "suit" means a set of garments composed of two or three pieces made up, in respect of their outer surface, pieces 	made up in identical fabric, put up for retail sale, and comprising: 	- one suit coat or jacket the outer shell of which, exclusive of sleeves, consists of four or more panels, designed to cover 		the upper part of the body, possibly with a tailored waistcoat in addition whose front is made from the same fabric as 		the outer surface of the other components of the set and whose back is made from the same fabric as the lining of the 		suit coat or jacket; and 	- one garment designed to cover the lower part of the body and consisting of trousers, breeches or shorts (other than 		swimwear), a skirt or a divided skirt, having neither braces nor bibs. 	All of the components of a "suit" must be of the same fabric construction, color and composition; they must also be of the 	same style and of corresponding or compatible size. However, these components may have piping (a strip of fabric sewn 	into the seam) in a different fabric. 	If several separate components to cover the lower part of the body area presented together (for example, two pairs of trousers 	or trousers and shorts, or a skirt or divided skirt and trousers), the constituent lower part shall be one pair of trousers, or, in 	the case of women's or girls' suits, the skirt or divided skirt, the other garments being considered separately. 	The term "suit" includes the following sets of garments whether or not they fulfill all the above conditions: 	- morning dress, comprising a plain jacket (cutaway) with rounded tails hanging well down at the back and striped trousers; 	- evening dress (tailcoat), generally made of black fabric, the jacket of which is relatively short at the front, does not close 		and has narrow skirts cut in at the hips and hanging down behind; 	- dinner jacket suits, in which the jacket is similar in style to an ordinary jacket (though perhaps revealing more of the shirt 		front), but has shiny silk or imitation silk lapels. (b) The term "ensemble" means a set of garments (other than suits and articles of heading 6207 or 6208) composed of several 	pieces made up in identical fabric, put up for retail sale, and comprising: 	- one garment designed to cover the upper part of the body, with the exception of waistcoats which may also form a 		second upper garment, and 	- one or two different garments, designed to cover the lower part of the body and consisting of trousers, bib and brace 		overalls, breeches, shorts (other than swimwear), a skirt or a divided skirt. 	All of the components of an ensemble must be of the same fabric construction, style, color and composition; they also must 	be of corresponding or compatible size. The term "ensemble" does not apply to track suits or ski-suits of heading 6211. 4. For the purposes of heading 6209: (a) The expression "babies' garments and clothing accessories" means articles for young children of a body height not exceeding 	86 centimeters; (b) Articles which are, prima facie, classifiable both in heading 6209 and in other headings of this chapter are to be classified 	in heading 6209. 5. Garments which are, prima facie, classifiable both in heading 6210 and in other headings of this chapter, excluding heading 	6209, are to be classified in heading 6210. 6. For the purposes of heading 6211,"ski-suits" means garments or sets of garments which, by their general appearance and 	texture, are identifiable as intended to be worn principally for skiing (cross-country or alpine). They consist either of: (a) A "ski overall," that is, a one-piece garment designed to cover the upper and the lower parts of the body; in addition to sleeves 	and a collar the ski overall may have pockets or footstraps; or (b) A "ski ensemble," that is, a set of garments composed of two or three pieces, put up for retail sale and comprising: 	- one garment such as an anorak, windbreaker or similar article, closed by a slide fastener (zipper), possibly with a 		waistcoat in addition, and 	- one pair of trousers whether or not extending above waist level, one pair of breeches or one bib and brace overall. 	The "ski ensemble" may also consist of an overall similar to the one mentioned in paragraph (a) above and a type of padded, 	sleeveless jacket worn over the overall. 	All the components of a "ski ensemble" must be made up in a fabric of the same texture, style and composition whether or 	not of the same color; they also must be of corresponding or compatible size. 7. Scarves and articles of the scarf type, square or approximately square, of which no side exceeds 60 centimeters, are to be 	classified as handkerchiefs (heading 6213). Handkerchiefs of which any side exceeds 60 centimeters are to be classified in 	heading 6214. 8. Garments of this chapter designed for left over right closure at the front shall be regarded as men's or boys' garments, and those 	designed for right over left closure at the front as women's or girls' garments. These provisions do not apply where the cut of the 	garment clearly indicates that it is designed for one or other of the sexes. 	Garments which cannot be identified as either men's or boys' garments or as women's or girls' garments are to be classified in 	the headings covering women's or girls' garments. 9. Articles of this chapter may be made of metal thread.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN63</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN63</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. Subchapter 1 applies only to made up articles, of any textile fabric. 2. Subchapter 1 does not cover: (a) Goods of chapters 56 to 62; or (b) Worn clothing or other worn articles of heading 6309. 3. Heading 6309 applies only to the following goods: (a) Articles of textile materials: 	(i) Clothing and clothing accessories, and parts thereof; 	(ii) Blankets and traveling rugs; 	(iii) Bed linen, table linen, toilet linen and kitchen linen; 	(iv) Furnishings, other than carpets of headings 5701 to 5705 and tapestries of heading 5805. (b) Footwear and headgear of any material other than asbestos. 	In order to be classified in this heading, the articles mentioned above must comply with both of the following requirements: 	(i) They must show signs of appreciable wear; and 	(ii) They must be entered in bulk or in bales, sacks or similar packing       Subheading Note      1. Subheading 6304.20 covers articles made from warp knit fabrics, impregnated or coated with alpha-cypermethrin (ISO), chlorfenapyr (ISO), deltamethrin (INN, ISO), lambda-cyhalothrin (ISO), permethrin (ISO), or pirimiphosmethyl (ISO).
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN64</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN64</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Disposable foot or shoe coverings of flimsy material (for example, paper, sheeting of plastics) without applied soles. These 	products are classified according to their constituent material; (b) Footwear of textile material, without an outer sole glued, sewn or otherwise affixed or applied to the upper (section XI); (c) Worn footwear of heading 6309; (d) Articles of asbestos (heading 6812); (e) Orthopedic footwear or other orthopedic appliances, or parts thereof (heading 9021) 1/; or (f) Toy footwear or skating boots with ice or roller skates attached; shin-guards or similar protective sportswear (chapter 95). 2. For the purposes of heading 6406, the term "parts" does not include pegs, protectors, eyelets, hooks, buckles, ornaments, braid, 	laces, pompons or other trimmings (which are to be classified in their appropriate headings) or buttons or other goods of heading 	9606. 3. For the purposes of this chapter: (a) the terms "rubber" and "plastics" include woven fabrics or other textile products with an external layer of rubber or plastics 	being visible to the naked eye; for the purpose of this provision, no account should be taken of any resulting change of color; 	and (b) the term "leather" refers to the goods of headings 4107 and 4112 to 4114. 4. Subject to note 3 to this chapter: (a) The material of the upper shall be taken to be the constituent material having the greatest external surface area, no account 	being taken of accessories or reinforcements such as ankle patches, edging, ornamentation, buckles, tabs, eyelet stays or 	similar attachments; (b) The constituent material of the outer sole shall be taken to be the material having the greatest surface area in contact with 	the ground, no account being taken of accessories or reinforcements such as spikes, bars, nails, protectors or similar 	attachments.  Subheading Note 1. For the purposes of subheadings 6402.12, 6402.19, 6403.12, 6403.19 and 6404.11, the expression "sports footwear" applies 	only to: (a) Footwear which is designed for a sporting activity and has, or has provision for the attachment of spikes, sprigs, cleats, 	stops, clips, bars or the like; (b) Skating boots, ski-boots and cross-country ski footwear, snowboard boots, wrestling boots, boxing boots and cycling shoes.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN65</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN65</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Worn headgear of heading 6309; (b) Asbestos headgear (heading 6812); or (c) Dolls' hats, other toy hats or carnival articles of chapter 95. 2. Heading 6502 does not cover hat shapes made by sewing, other than those obtained simply by sewing strips in spirals.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN66</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN66</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Measure walking-sticks or the like (heading 9017); (b) Firearm-sticks, sword-sticks, loaded walking-sticks or the like (chapter 93); or (c) Goods of chapter 95 (for example, toy umbrellas, toy sun umbrellas). 2. Heading 6603 does not cover parts, trimmings or accessories of textile material, or covers, tassels, thongs, umbrella cases or 	the like, of any material. Such goods entered with, but not fitted to, articles of heading 6601 or 6602 are to be classified separately 	and are not to be treated as forming part of those articles.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN67</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN67</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Straining cloth of human hair (heading 5911); (b) Floral motifs of lace, of embroidery or other textile fabric (section XI); (c) Footwear (chapter 64); (d) Headgear or hair-nets (chapter 65); (e) Toys, sports equipment, or carnival articles (chapter 95); or (f) Feather dusters, powder-puffs or hair sieves (chapter 96). 2. Heading 6701 does not cover: (a) Articles in which feathers or down constitute only filling or padding (for example, bedding of heading 9404); (b) Articles of apparel or clothing accessories in which feathers or down constitute no more than mere trimming, filling or padding; 	or (c) Artificial flowers or foliage or parts thereof or made up articles of heading 6702. 3. Heading 6702 does not cover: (a) Articles of glass (chapter 70); or (b) Artificial flowers, foliage or fruit of pottery, stone, metal, wood or other materials, obtained in one piece by molding, forging, 	carving, stamping or other process, or consisting of parts assembled otherwise than by binding, gluing, fitting into one another 	or similar methods.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN68</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN68</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Goods of chapter 25; (b) Coated, impregnated or covered paper and paperboard of heading 4810 or 4811 (for example, paper and paperboard coated 	with mica powder or graphite, bituminized or asphalted paper and paperboard); (c) Coated, impregnated or covered textile fabric of chapter 56 or 59 (for example, fabric coated or covered with mica powder, 	bituminized or asphalted fabric); (d) Articles of chapter 71; (e) Tools or parts of tools, of chapter 82; (f) Lithographic stones of heading 8442; (g) Electrical insulators (heading 8546) or fittings of insulating material of heading 8547; (h) Dental burrs (heading 9018); (ij) Articles of chapter 91 (for example, clocks and clock cases); (k) Articles of chapter 94 (for example, furniture, lamps and lighting fittings, prefabricated buildings); (l) Articles of chapter 95 (for example, toys, games and sports equipment); (m) Articles of heading 9602, if made of materials specified in note 2(b) to chapter 96; or of heading 9606 (for example, buttons), 	9609 (for example, slate pencils) or 9610 (for example, drawing slates); or (n) Articles of chapter 97 (for example, works of art). 2. In heading 6802 the expression "worked monumental or building stone" applies not only to the varieties of stone referred to in 	heading 2515 or 2516, but also to all other natural stone (for example, quartzite, flint, dolomite and steatite) similarly worked; it 	does not, however, apply to slate.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN69</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN69</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter applies only to ceramic products which have been fired after shaping. Headings 6904 to 6914 apply only to such 	products other than those classifiable in headings 6901 to 6903. 2. This chapter does not cover: (a) Products of heading 2844; (b) Articles of heading 6804; (c) Articles of chapter 71 (for example, imitation jewelry); (d) Cermets of heading 8113; (e) Articles of chapter 82; (f) Electrical insulators (heading 8546) or fittings of insulating material (heading 8547); (g) Artificial teeth (heading 9021); (h) Articles of chapter 91 (for example, clocks and clock cases); (ij) Articles of chapter 94 (for example, furniture, lamps and lighting fittings, prefabricated buildings); (k) Articles of chapter 95 (for example, toys, games and sports equipment); (l) Articles of heading 9606 (for example, buttons) or of heading 9614 (for example, smoking pipes); or (m) Articles of chapter 97 (for example, works of art).
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN70</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN70</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Goods of heading 3207 (for example, vitrifiable enamels and glazes, glass frit, other glass in the form of powder, granules 	or flakes); (b) Articles of chapter 71 (for example, imitation jewelry); (c) Optical fiber cables of heading 8544, electrical insulators (heading 8546) or fittings of insulating material of heading 8547; (d) Optical fibers, optically worked optical elements, hypodermic syringes, artificial eyes, thermometers, barometers, hydrometers 	or other articles of chapter 90; (e) Lamps or lighting fittings, illuminated signs, illuminated name-plates or the like, having a permanently fixed light source, or 	parts thereof of heading 9405; (f) Toys, games, sports equipment, Christmas tree ornaments or other articles of chapter 95 (excluding glass eyes without 	mechanisms for dolls or for other articles of chapter 95); or (g) Buttons, fitted vacuum flasks, scent or similar sprays or other articles of chapter 96. 2. For the purposes of headings 7003, 7004 and 7005: (a) Glass is not regarded as "worked" by reason of any process it has undergone before annealing; (b) Cutting to shape does not affect the classification of glass in sheets; (c) The expression "absorbent, reflecting or non-reflecting layer" means a microscopically thin coating of metal or of a chemical 	compound (for example, metal oxide) which absorbs, for example, infrared light; or which improves the reflecting qualities 	of the glass while still allowing it to retain a degree of transparency or translucency; or which prevents light from being 	reflected on the surface of the glass. 3. The products referred to in heading 7006 remain classified in that heading whether or not they have the character of articles. 4. For the purposes of heading 7019, the expression "glass wool" means: (a) Mineral wools with a silica (SiO2) content not less than 60 percent by weight; (b) Mineral wools with a silica (SiO2) content less than 60 percent but with an alkaline oxide (K2O or Na2O) content exceeding 	5 percent by weight or a borix oxide (B2O3) content exceeding 2 percent by weight. 	Mineral wools which do not comply with the above specifications fall in heading 6806. 5. Throughout the tariff schedule, the expression "glass" includes fused quartz and other fused silica.  Subheading Note 1. For the purposes of subheadings 7013.22, 7013.33, 7013.41 and 7013.91, the expression "lead crystal" means only glass having 	a minimum lead monoxide (PbO) content by weight of 24 percent.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN71</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN71</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. Subject to note 1(a) to section VI and except as provided below, all articles consisting wholly or partly: (a) Of natural or cultured pearls or of precious or semiprecious stones (natural, synthetic or reconstructed), or (b) Of precious metal or of metal clad with precious metal, are to be classified in this chapter. 2. (a) Headings 7113, 7114 and 7115 do not cover articles in which precious metal or metal clad with precious metal is present 	as minor constituents only, such as minor fittings or minor ornamentation (for example, monograms, ferrules and rims), and 	paragraph (b) of the foregoing note does not apply to such articles. (b) Heading 7116 does not cover articles containing precious metal or metal clad with precious metal (other than as minor 	constituents). 3. This chapter does not cover: (a) Amalgams of precious metal or colloidal precious metal (heading 2843); (b) Sterile surgical suture materials, dental fillings or other goods of chapter 30; (c) Goods of chapter 32 (for example, lustres); (d) Supported catalysts (heading 3815); (e) Articles of heading 4202 or 4203 referred to in note 3(B) to chapter 42; (f) Articles of heading 4303 or 4304; (g) Goods of section XI (textiles and textile articles); (h) Footwear, headgear or other articles of chapter 64 or 65; (ij) Umbrellas, walking-sticks or other articles of chapter 66; (k) Abrasive goods of heading 6804 or 6805 or chapter 82, containing dust or powder of precious or semiprecious stones (natural 	or synthetic); articles of chapter 82 with a working part of precious or semiprecious stones (natural, synthetic or reconstructed); 	machinery, mechanical appliances or electrical goods, or parts thereof, of section XVI. However, articles and parts thereof, 	wholly of precious or semiprecious stones (natural, synthetic or reconstructed) remain classified in this chapter, except 	unmounted worked sapphires and diamonds for styli (heading 8522); (l) Articles of chapter 90, 91 or 92 (scientific instruments, clocks and watches, musical instruments); (m) Arms or parts thereof (chapter 93); (n) Articles covered by note 2 to chapter 95; (o) Articles classified in chapter 96 by virtue of note 4 to that chapter; or (p) Original sculptures or statuary (heading 9703), collectors' pieces (heading 9705) or antiques of an age exceeding one hundred 	years (heading 9706), other than natural or cultured pearls or precious or semiprecious stones. 4.  (a) The expression "precious metal" means silver, gold and platinum. (b) The expression "platinum" means platinum, iridium, osmium, palladium, rhodium and ruthenium. (c) The expression "precious or semiprecious stones" does not include any of the substances specified in note 2(b) to chapter 96. 5. For the purposes of this chapter, any alloy (including a sintered mixture and an inter-metallic compound) containing precious 	metal is to be treated as an alloy of precious metal if any one precious metal constitutes as much as 2 percent, by weight, of the 	alloy. Alloys of precious metal are to be classified according to the following rules: (a) An alloy containing 2 percent or more, by weight, of platinum is to be treated as an alloy of platinum; (b) An alloy containing 2 percent or more, by weight, of gold but no platinum, or less than 2 percent, by weight, of platinum, is 	to be treated as an alloy of gold; (c) Other alloys containing 2 percent or more, by weight, of silver are to be treated as alloys of silver. 6. Except where the context otherwise requires, any reference in the tariff schedule to precious metal or to any particular precious 	metal includes a reference to alloys treated as alloys of precious metal or of the particular metal in accordance with the rules in 	note 5 above, but not to metal clad with precious metal or to base metal or non-metals plated with precious metal. 7. Throughout the tariff schedule the expression "metal clad with precious metal" means material made with a base of metal upon 	one or more surfaces of which there is affixed by soldering, brazing, welding, hot-rolling or similar mechanical means a covering 	of precious metal. Except where the context otherwise requires, the expression also covers base metal inlaid with precious metal. 8. Subject to note 1(a) to section VI, goods answering to a description in heading 7112 are to be classified in that heading and in 	no other heading of the tariff schedule. 9. For the purposes of heading 7113, the expression "articles of jewelry" means: (a) Any small objects of personal adornment (for example, rings, bracelets, necklaces, brooches, earrings, watch chains, fobs, 	pendants, tie pins, cuff links, dress studs, religious or other medals and insignia); and (b) Articles of personal use of a kind normally carried in the pocket, in the handbag or on the person (for example, cigar or 	cigarette cases, snuff boxes, cachou or pill boxes, powder boxes, chain purses or prayer beads). 	These articles may be combined or set, for example, with natural or cultured pearls, precious or semiprecious stones, synthetic 	or reconstructed precious or semiprecious stones, tortoise shell, mother-of-pearl, ivory, natural or reconstituted amber, jet or 	coral. 10. For the purposes of heading 7114, the expression "articles of goldsmiths' or silversmiths' wares" includes such articles as 	ornaments, tableware, toilet-ware, smokers' articles and other articles of household, office or religious use. 11. For the purposes of heading 7117, the expression "imitation jewelry" means articles of jewelry within the meaning of paragraph (a) of note 9 above (but not including buttons or other articles of heading 9606, or dress combs, hair slides or the like, or hairpins, 	of heading 9615), not incorporating natural or cultured pearls, precious or semiprecious stones (natural, synthetic or reconstructed) 	nor (except as plating or as minor constituents) precious metal or metal clad with precious metal.  Subheading Notes 1. For the purposes of subheadings 7106.10, 7108.11, 7110.11, 7110.21, 7110.31 and 7110.41, the expressions "powder" and "in 	powder form" mean products of which 90 percent or more by weight passes through a sieve having a mesh aperture of 0.5 mm. 2. Notwithstanding the provisions of note 4(b), for the purposes of subheadings 7110.11 and 7110.19, the expression "platinum" 	does not include iridium, osmium, palladium, rhodium or ruthenium. 3. For the classification of alloys in the subheadings of heading 7110, each alloy is to be classified with that metal, platinum, 	palladium, rhodium, iridium, osmium or ruthenium, which predominates by weight over each other of these metals.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN72</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN72</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. In this chapter and, in the case of notes (d), (e) and (f) below throughout the tariff schedule, the following expressions have the 	meanings hereby assigned to them: (a) Pig iron 	Iron-carbon alloys not usefully malleable, containing more than 2 percent by weight of carbon and which may contain by 	weight one or more other elements within the following limits: 	- not more than 10 percent of chromium 	- not more than 6 percent of manganese 	- not more than 3 percent of phosphorus 	- not more than 8 percent of silicon 	- a total of not more than 10 percent of other elements. (b) Spiegeleisen 	Iron-carbon alloys containing by weight more than 6 percent but not more than 30 percent of manganese and otherwise 	conforming to the specification at (a) above. (c) Ferroalloys 	Alloys in pigs, blocks, lumps or similar primary forms, in forms obtained by continuous casting and also in granular or powder 	forms, whether or not agglomerated, commonly used as an additive in the manufacture of other alloys or as deoxidants, 	desulfurizing agents or for similar uses in ferrous metallurgy and generally not usefully malleable, containing by weight 4 	percent or more of the element iron and one or more of the following: 	- more than 10 percent of chromium 	- more than 30 percent of manganese 	- more than 3 percent of phosphorus 	- more than 8 percent of silicon 	- a total of more than 10 percent of other elements, excluding carbon, subject to a maximum content of 10 percent in the 	case of copper. (d) Steel 	Ferrous materials other than those of heading 7203 which (with the exception of certain types produced in the form of castings) 	are usefully malleable and which contain by weight 2 percent or less of carbon. However, chromium steels may contain higher 	proportions of carbon. 	(e) Stainless steel 	Alloy steels containing, by weight 1.2 percent or less of carbon and 10.5 percent or more of chromium, with or without other 	elements. (f) Other alloy steel 	Steels not complying with the definition of stainless steel and containing by weight one or more of the following elements in 	the proportion shown: 	- 0.3 percent or more of aluminum 	- 0.0008 percent or more of boron 	- 0.3 percent or more of chromium 	- 0.3 percent or more of cobalt 	- 0.4 percent or more of copper 	- 0.4 percent or more of lead 	- 1.65 percent or more of manganese 	- 0.08 percent or more of molybdenum 	- 0.3 percent or more of nickel 	- 0.06 percent or more of niobium 	- 0.6 percent or more of silicon. 	- 0.05 percent or more of titanium 	- 0.3 percent or more of tungsten (wolfram) 	- 0.1 percent or more of vanadium 	- 0.05 percent or more of zirconium 	- 0.1 percent or more of other elements (except sulfur, phosphorus, carbon and nitrogen), taken separately. (g) Remelting scrap ingots of iron or steel 	Products roughly cast in the form of ingots without feeder-heads or hot tops, or of pigs, having obvious surface faults and 	not complying with the chemical composition of pig iron, spiegeleisen or ferroalloys. (h) Granules 	Products of which less than 90 percent by weight passes through a sieve with a mesh aperture of 1 mm and of which 90 	percent or more by weight passes through a sieve with a mesh aperture of 5 mm. (ij) Semifinished products 	Continuous cast products of solid section, whether or not subjected to primary hot-rolling; and 	Other products of solid section, which have not been further worked than subjected to primary hot-rolling or roughly shaped 	by forging, including blanks for angles, shapes or sections. 	These products are not presented in coils. (k) Flat-rolled products 	Rolled products of solid rectangular (other than square) cross section, which do not conform to the definition at (ij) above in 	the form of: 	- coils of successively superimposed layers, or 	- straight lengths, which if of a thickness less than 4.75 mm are of a width measuring at least 10 times the thickness or if of 	a thickness of 4.75 mm or more are of a width which exceeds 150 mm and measures at least twice the thickness. 	Flat-rolled products include those with patterns in relief derived directly from rolling (for example, grooves, ribs, checkers, 	tears, buttons, lozenges) and those which have been perforated, corrugated or polished, provided that they do not thereby 	assume the character of articles or products of other headings. 	Flat-rolled products of a shape other than rectangular or square, of any size, are to be classified as products of a width of 	600 mm or more, provided that they do not assume the character of articles or products of other headings. (l) Bars and rods, hot-rolled, in irregularly wound coils 	Hot-rolled products in irregularly wound coils, which have a solid cross section in the shape of circles, segments of circles, 	ovals, rectangles (including squares), triangles or other convex polygons (including "flattened circles" and "modified rectangles", 	of which two opposite sides are convex arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal length and parallel).These products 	may have indentations, ribs, grooves or other deformations produced during the rolling process (reinforcing bars and rods). (m) Other bars and rods 	Products which do not conform to any of the definitions at (ij), (k) or (l) above or to the definition of wire, which have a uniform 	solid cross section along their whole length in the shape of circles, segments of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), 	triangles or other convex polygons (including "flattened circles" and "modified rectangles", of which two opposite sides are 	convex arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal length and parallel). These products may: 	- have indentations, ribs, grooves or other deformations produced during the rolling process (reinforcing bars and rods); 	- be twisted after rolling. (n) Angles, shapes and sections 	Products having a uniform solid cross section along their whole length which do not conform to any of the definitions at (ij), 	(k), (l) or (m) above or to the definition of wire. 	Chapter 72 does not include products of heading 7301 or 7302. (o) Wire 	Cold-formed products in coils, of any uniform solid cross section along their whole length, which do not conform to the definition 	of flat-rolled products. (p) Hollow drill bars and rods 	Hollow bars and rods of any cross section, suitable for drills, of which the greatest external dimension of the cross section 	exceeds 15 mm but does not exceed 52 mm, and of which the greatest internal dimension does not exceed one half of the 	greatest external dimension. Hollow bars and rods of iron or steel not conforming to this definition are to be classified in 	heading 7304. 2. Ferrous metals clad with another ferrous metal are to be classified as products of the ferrous metal predominating by weight. 3. Iron or steel products obtained by electrolytic deposition, by pressure casting or by sintering are to be classified according to 	their form, their composition and their appearance, in the headings of this chapter appropriate to similar hot-rolled products.  Subheading Notes 1. In this chapter the following expressions have the meanings hereby assigned to them: (a) Alloy pig iron 	Pig iron containing, by weight, one or more of the following elements in the specified proportions: 	- more than 0.2 percent of chromium 	- more than 0.3 percent of copper 	- more than 0.3 percent of nickel 	- more than 0.1 percent of any of the following elements: aluminum, molybdenum, titanium, tungsten (wolfram), vanadium. (b) Nonalloy free-cutting steel 	Nonalloy steel containing by weight one or more of the following elements in the specified proportions: 	- 0
.08 percent or more of sulfur 	- 0.1 percent or more of lead 	- more than 0.05 percent of selenium 	- more than 0.01 percent of tellurium 	- more than 0.05 percent of bismuth. (c) Silicon electrical steel 	Alloy steels containing by weight at least 0.6 percent but not more than 6 percent of silicon and not more than 0.08 percent 	of carbon. They may also contain by weight not more than 1 percent of aluminum but no other element in a proportion that 	would give the steel the characteristics of another alloy steel. (d) High-speed steel 	Alloy steels containing, with or without other elements, at least two of the three elements molybdenum, tungsten and vanadium 	with a combined content by weight of 7 percent or more, 0.6 percent or more of carbon and 3 to 6 percent of chromium. (e) Silico-manganese steel 	Alloy steels containing by weight: 	- not more than 0.7 percent of carbon, 	- 0.5 percent or more but not more than 1.9 percent of manganese, and 	- 0.6 percent or more but not more than 2.3 percent of silicon, but no other element in a proportion that would give the steel 	the characteristics of another alloy steel. 2. For the classification of ferroalloys in the subheadings of heading 7202 the following rule should be observed: 	A ferroalloy is considered as binary and classified under the relevant subheading (if it exists) if only one of the alloy elements 	exceeds the minimum percentage laid down in chapter note 1(c); by analogy, it is considered respectively as ternary or quaternary 	if two or three alloy elements exceed the minimum percentage. 	For the application of this rule, the unspecified "other elements" referred to in chapter note 1(c) must each exceed 10 percent by 	weight.</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN73</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN73</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. In this chapter the expression "cast iron" applies to products obtained by casting in which iron predominates by weight over each 	of the other elements and which do not comply with the chemical composition of steel as defined in Note 1(d) to chapter 72. 2. In this chapter the word "wire" means hot- or cold-formed products of any cross-sectional shape, of which no cross-sectional 	dimension exceeds 16 mm.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN74</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN74</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Note 1. In this chapter the following expressions have the meanings hereby assigned to them: (a) Refined copper 	Metal containing at least 99.85 percent by weight of copper; or 	Metal containing at least 97.5 percent by weight of copper, provided that the content by weight of any other element does 	not exceed the limit specified in the following table:  TABLE - Other elements _____________________________________________________________ Element					Limiting content % by weight Ag	Silver				0.25 As	Arsenic				0.5 Cd	Cadmium				1.3 Cr	Chromium			1.4 Mg	Magnesium			0.8 Pb	Lead				1.5 S	Sulphur				0.7 Sn	Tin					0.8 Te	Tellurium			0.8 Zn	Zinc				1 Zr	Zirconium			0.3 Other elements*, each	 	0.3 ______________________________________________________________ * Other elements are, for example, Al, Be, Co, Fe, Mn, Ni, Si.  (b) Copper alloys 	Metallic substances other than unrefined copper in which copper predominates by weight over each of the other elements, 	provided that: 	(i) The content by weight of at least one of the other elements is greater than the limit specified in the foregoing table; or 	(ii) The total content by weight of such other elements exceeds 2.5 percent. (c) Master alloys 	Alloys containing with other elements more than 10 percent by weight of copper, not usefully malleable and commonly used 	as an additive in the manufacture of other alloys or as deoxidants, desulfurizing agents or for similar uses in the metallurgy 	of nonferrous metals. However, copper phosphide (phosphor copper) containing more than 15 percent by weight of phosphorus 	falls in heading 2848. (d) Bars and rods 	Rolled, extruded, drawn or forged products, not in coils, which have a uniform solid cross section along their whole length in 	the shape of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), equilateral triangles or regular convex polygons (including "flattened 	circles" and "modified rectangles", of which two opposite sides are convex arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal 	length and parallel). Products with a rectangular (including square), triangular or polygonal cross section may have corners 	rounded along their whole length.The thickness of such products which have a rectangular (including "modified rectangular") 	cross section exceeds one-tenth of the width. The expression also covers cast or sintered products, of the same forms and 	dimensions, which have been subsequently worked after production (otherwise than by simple trimming or descaling), provided 	that they have not thereby assumed the character of articles or products of other headings. 	Wire bars and billets with their ends tapered or otherwise worked simply to facilitate their entry into machines for converting 	them into, for example, drawing stock (wire rod) or tubes, are, however, to be taken to be unwrought copper of heading 7403. (e) Profiles 	Rolled, extruded, drawn, forged or formed products, coiled or not, of a uniform cross section along their whole length, which 	do not conform to any of the definitions of bars, rods, wire, plates, sheets, strip, foil, tubes or pipes. The expression also 	covers cast or sintered products, of the same forms, which have been subsequently worked after production (otherwise than 	by simple trimming or descaling), provided that they have not thereby assumed the character of articles or products of other 	headings. (f) Wire 	Rolled, extruded or drawn products, in coils, which have a uniform solid cross section along their whole length in the shape 	of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), equilateral triangles or regular convex polygons (including "flattened circles" 	and "modified rectangles", of which two opposite sides are convex arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal length 	and parallel). Products with a rectangular (including square), triangular or polygonal cross section may have corners rounded 	along their whole length. The thickness of such products which have a rectangular (including "modified rectangular") cross 	section exceeds one-tenth of the width. (g) Plates, sheets, strip and foil 	Flat-surfaced products (other than the unwrought products of heading 7403), coiled or not, of solid rectangular (other than 	square) cross section with or without rounded corners (including "modified rectangles" of which two opposite sides are convex 	arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal length and parallel) of a uniform thickness, which are: 		- of rectangular (including square) shape with a thickness not exceeding one-tenth of the width, 		- of a shape other than rectangular or square, of any size, provided that they do not assume the character of articles or 		products of other headings. 	Headings 7409 and 7410 apply, inter alia , to plates, sheets, strip and foil with patterns (for example, grooves, ribs, checkers, 	tears, buttons, lozenges) and to such products which have been perforated, corrugated, polished or coated, provided that 	they do not thereby assume the character of articles or products of other headings. (h) Tubes and pipes 	Hollow products, coiled or not, which have a uniform cross section with only one enclosed void along their whole length in 	the shape of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), equilateral triangles or regular convex polygons, and which have 	a uniform wall thickness. Products with a rectangular (including square), equilateral triangular or regular convex polygonal 	cross section, which may have corners rounded along their whole length, are also to be taken to be tubes and pipes provided 	the inner and outer cross sections are concentric and have the same form and orientation. Tubes and pipes of the foregoing 	cross sections may be polished, coated, bent, threaded, drilled, waisted, expanded, cone-shaped or fitted with flanges, collars 	or rings.  Subheading Note 1. In this chapter the following expressions have the meanings hereby assigned to them: (a) Copper-zinc base alloys (brasses) 	Alloys of copper and zinc, with or without other elements.When other elements are present: 	- zinc predominates by weight over each of such other elements; 	- any nickel content by weight is less than 5 percent (see copper-nickel-zinc alloys (nickel silvers)); and 	- any tin content by weight is less than 3 percent (see copper-tin alloys (bronzes)). (b) Copper-tin base alloys (bronzes) 	Alloys of copper and tin, with or without other elements.When other elements are present, tin predominates by weight over 	each of such other elements, except that when the tin content is 3 percent or more the zinc content by weight may exceed 	that of tin but must be less than 10 percent. (c) Copper-nickel-zinc base alloys (nickel silvers) 	Alloys of copper, nickel and zinc, with or without other elements. The nickel content is 5 percent or more by weight (see 	copper-zinc alloys (brasses)). (d) Copper-nickel base alloys 	Alloys of copper and nickel, with or without other elements but in any case containing by weight not more than 1 percent of 	zinc.When other elements are present, nickel predominates by weight over each of such other elements.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN75</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN75</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Note 1. In this chapter the following expressions have the meanings hereby assigned to them: (a) Bars and rods 	Rolled, extruded, drawn or forged products, not in coils, which have a uniform solid cross section along their whole length in 	the shape of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), equilateral triangles or regular convex polygons (including "flattened 	circles" and "modified rectangles", of which two opposite sides are convex arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal 	length and parallel). Products with a rectangular (including square), triangular or polygonal cross section may have corners 	rounded along their whole length.The thickness of such products which have a rectangular (including "modified rectangular") 	cross section exceeds one-tenth of the width. The expression also covers cast or sintered products, of the same forms and 	dimensions, which have been subsequently worked after production (otherwise than by simple trimming or descaling), provided 	that they have not thereby assumed the character of articles or products of other headings. (b) Profiles 	Rolled, extruded, drawn, forged or formed products, coiled or not, of a uniform cross section along their whole length, which 	do not conform to any of the definitions of bars, rods, wire, plates, sheets, strip, foil, tubes or pipes. The expression also 	covers cast or sintered products, of the same forms, which have been subsequently worked after production (otherwise than 	by simple trimming or descaling), provided that they have not thereby assumed the character of articles or products of other 	headings. (c) Wire 	Rolled, extruded or drawn products, in coils, which have a uniform solid cross section along their whole length in the shape 	of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), equilateral triangles or regular convex polygons (including "flattened circles" 	and "modified rectangles", of which two opposite sides are convex arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal length 	and parallel). Products with a rectangular (including square), triangular or polygonal cross section may have corners rounded 	along their whole length. The thickness of such products which have a rectangular (including "modified rectangular") cross 	section exceeds one-tenth of the width. (d) Plates, sheets, strip and foil 	Flat-surfaced products (other than the unwrought products of heading 7502), coiled or not, of solid rectangular (other than 	square) cross section with or without rounded corners (including "modified rectangles" of which two opposite sides are convex 	arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal length and parallel) of a uniform thickness, which are: 		- of rectangular (including square) shape with a thickness not exceeding one-tenth of the width, 		- of a shape other than rectangular or square, of any size, provided that they do not assume the character of articles or of 		products of other headings. 	Heading 7506 applies, inter alia, to plates, sheets, strip and foil with patterns (for example, grooves, ribs, checkers, tears, 	buttons, lozenges) and to such products which have been perforated, corrugated, polished or coated, provided that they do 	not thereby assume the character of articles or of products of other headings. (e) Tubes and pipes 	Hollow products, coiled or not, which have a uniform cross section with only one enclosed void along their whole length in 	the shape of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), equilateral triangles or regular convex polygons, and which have 	a uniform wall thickness. Products with a rectangular (including square), equilateral triangular or regular convex polygonal 	cross section, which may have corners rounded along their whole length, are also to be taken to be tubes and pipes provided 	the inner and outer cross sections are concentric and have the same form and orientation. Tubes and pipes of the foregoing 	cross sections may be polished, coated, bent, threaded, drilled, waisted, expanded, cone-shaped or fitted with flanges, collars 	or rings.  Subheading Notes 1. In this chapter the following expressions have the meanings hereby assigned to them: (a) Nickel, not alloyed 	Metal containing by weight at least 99 percent of nickel plus cobalt, provided that: 	(i) The cobalt content by weight does not exceed 1.5 percent, and 	(ii) The content by weight of any other element does not exceed the limit specified in the following table:  TABLE - Other elements __________________________________________________ Element				Limiting content % by weight Fe	Iron			0.5 O	Oxygen			0.4 Other elements, each	 	0.3 __________________________________________________  (b) Nickel alloys 	Metallic substances in which nickel predominates by weight over each of the other elements provided that: 	(i) The content by weight of cobalt exceeds 1.5 percent, 	(ii) The content by weight of at least one of the other elements is greater than the limit specified in the foregoing table, or 	(iii) The total content by weight of elements other than nickel plus cobalt exceeds 1 percent. 2. Notwithstanding the provisions of chapter note 1(c), for the purposes of subheading 7508.10 the term "wire" applies only to 	products, whether or not in coils, of any cross-sectional shape, of which no cross-sectional dimension exceeds 6 mm.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN76</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN76</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Note 1. In this chapter the following expressions have the meanings hereby assigned to them: (a) Bars and rods 	Rolled, extruded, drawn or forged products, not in coils, which have a uniform solid cross section along their whole length in 	the shape of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), equilateral triangles or regular convex polygons (including "flattened 	circles" and "modified rectangles", of which two opposite sides are convex arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal 	length and parallel). Products with a rectangular (including square), triangular or polygonal cross section may have corners 	rounded along their whole length.The thickness of such products which have a rectangular (including "modified rectangular") 	cross section exceeds one-tenth of the width. The expression also covers cast or sintered products, of the same forms and 	dimensions, which have been subsequently worked after production (otherwise than by simple trimming or descaling), provided 	that they have not thereby assumed the character of articles or products of other headings. (b) Profiles 	Rolled, extruded, drawn, forged or formed products, coiled or not, of a uniform cross section along their whole length, which 	do not conform to any of the definitions of bars, rods, wire, plates, sheets, strip, foil, tubes or pipes. The expression also 	covers cast or sintered products, of the same forms, which have been subsequently worked after production (otherwise than 	by simple trimming or descaling), provided that they have not thereby assumed the character of articles or products of other 	headings. (c) Wire 	Rolled, extruded or drawn products, in coils, which have a uniform solid cross section along their whole length in the shape 	of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), equilateral triangles or regular convex polygons (including "flattened circles" 	and "modified rectangles", of which two opposite sides are convex arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal length 	and parallel). Products with a rectangular (including square), triangular or polygonal cross section may have corners rounded 	along their whole length. The thickness of such products which have a rectangular (including "modified rectangular") cross 	section exceeds one-tenth of the width. (d) Plates, sheets, strip and foil 	Flat-surfaced products (other than the unwrought products of heading 7601), coiled or not, of solid rectangular (other than 	square) cross section with or without rounded corners (including "modified rectangles" of which two opposite sides are convex 	arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal length and parallel) of a uniform thickness, which are: 		- of rectangular (including square) shape with a thickness not exceeding one-tenth of the width, 		- of a shape other than rectangular or square, of any size, provided that they do not assume the character of articles or 		products of other headings. 	Headings 7606 and 7607 apply, inter alia , to plates, sheets, strip and foil with patterns (for example, grooves, ribs, checkers, 	tears, buttons, lozenges) and to such products which have been perforated, corrugated, polished or coated, provided that 	they do not thereby assume the character of articles or products of other headings. (e) Tubes and pipes 	Hollow products, coiled or not, which have a uniform cross section with only one enclosed void along their whole length in 	the shape of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), equilateral triangles or regular convex polygons, and which have 	a uniform wall thickness. Products with a rectangular (including square), equilateral triangular or regular convex polygonal 	cross section, which may have corners rounded along their whole length, are also to be considered as tubes and pipes 	provided the inner and outer cross sections are concentric and have the same form and orientation. Tubes and pipes of the 	foregoing cross sections may be polished, coated, bent, threaded, drilled, waisted, expanded, cone-shaped or fitted with 	flanges, collars or rings.  Subheading Notes 1. In this chapter the following expressions have the meanings hereby assigned to them: (a) Aluminum, not alloyed 	Metal containing by weight at least 99 percent of aluminum, provided that the content by weight of any other element does 	not exceed the limit specified in the following table:  TABLE - Other elements ____________________________________________________________________________________________ Element                                                 	Limiting content % by weight Fe + Si (iron plus silicon)									1 Other elements (1), each									0.1 (2) ____________________________________________________________________________________________ (1)     Other elements are, for example Cr, Cu, Mg, Mn, Ni, Zn. (2)     Copper is permitted in a proportion greater than 0.1 % but not more than 0.2 %,  		provided that neither the chromium nor manganese content exceeds 0.05 %. ____________________________________________________________________________________________		  (b) Aluminum alloys 	Metallic substances in which aluminum predominates by weight over each of the other elements, provided that: 	(i) The content by weight of at least one of the other elements or of iron plus silicon taken together is greater than the limit 		specified in the foregoing table; or 	(ii) The total content by weight of such other elements exceeds 1 percent. 2. Notwithstanding the provisions of chapter note 1(c), for the purposes of subheading 7616.91 the term "wire" applies only to 	products, whether or not in coils, of any cross-sectional shape, of which no cross-sectional dimension exceeds 6 mm.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN78</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN78</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Note 1. In this chapter the following expressions have the meanings hereby assigned to them: (a) Bar and rods 	Rolled, extruded, drawn or forged products, not in coils, which have a uniform solid cross section along their whole length in 	the shape of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), equilateral triangles or regular convex polygons (including "flattened 	circles" and "modified rectangles", of which two opposite sides are convex arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal 	length and parallel). Products with a rectangular (including square), triangular or polygonal cross section may have corners 	rounded along their whole length.The thickness of such products which have a rectangular (including "modified rectangular") 	cross section exceeds one-tenth of the width. The expression also covers cast or sintered products, of the same forms and 	dimensions, which have been subsequently worked after production (otherwise than by simple trimming or descaling), provided 	that they have not thereby assumed the character of articles or products of other headings. (b) Profiles 	Rolled, extruded, drawn, forged or formed products, coiled or not, of a uniform cross section along their whole length, which 	do not conform to any of the definitions of bars, rods, wire, plates, sheets, strip, foil, tubes or pipes. The expression also 	covers cast or sintered products, of the same forms, which have been subsequently worked after production (otherwise than 	by simple trimming or descaling), provided that they have not thereby assumed the character of articles or products of other 	headings. (c) Wire 	Rolled, extruded or drawn products, in coils, which have a uniform solid cross section along their whole length in the shape 	of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), equilateral triangles or regular convex polygons (including "flattened circles" 	and "modified rectangles", of which two opposite sides are convex arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal length 	and parallel). Products with a rectangular (including square), triangular or polygonal cross section may have corners rounded 	along their whole length. The thickness of such products which have a rectangular (including "modified rectangular") cross 	section exceeds one-tenth of the width. (d) Plates, sheets, strip and foil 	Flat-surfaced products (other than the unwrought products of heading 7801), coiled or not, of solid rectangular (other than 	square) cross section with or without rounded corners (including "modified rectangles" of which two opposite sides are convex 	arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal length and parallel) of a uniform thickness, which are: 		- of rectangular (including square) shape with a thickness not exceeding one-tenth of the width, 		- of a shape other than rectangular or square, of any size, provided that they do not assume the character of articles or 		products of other headings. 	Heading 7804 applies, inter alia , to plates, sheets, strip and foil with patterns (for example, grooves, ribs, checkers, tears, 	buttons, lozenges) and to such products which have been perforated, corrugated, polished or coated, provided that they do 	not thereby assume the character of articles or products of other headings. (e) Tubes and pipes 	Hollow products, coiled or not, which have a uniform cross section with only one enclosed void along their whole length in 	the shape of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), equilateral triangles or regular convex polygons, and which have 	a uniform wall thickness. Products with a rectangular (including square), equilateral triangular or regular convex polygonal 	cross section, which may have corners rounded along their whole length, are also to be considered as tubes and pipes 	provided the inner and outer cross sections are concentric and have the same form and orientation. Tubes and pipes of the 	foregoing cross sections may be polished, coated, bent, threaded, drilled, waisted, expanded, cone-shaped or fitted with 	flanges, collars or rings.  Subheading Note 1. In this chapter the expression "refined lead" means: 	Metal containing by weight at least 99.9 percent of lead, provided that the content by weight of any other element does not exceed 	the limit specified in the following table:  TABLE - Other elements _________________________________________________ Element				Limiting content % by weight Ag	Silver							0.02 As	Arsenic							0.005 Bi	Bismuth							0.05 Ca	Calcium							0.002 Cd	Cadmium							0.002 Cu	Copper							0.08 Fe	Iron							0.002 S	Sulphur							0.002 Sb	Antimony						0.005 Sn	Tin								0.005 Zn	Zinc							0.002 Other (for example Te), each		0.001 __________________________________________________
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN79</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN79</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Note 1. In this chapter the following expressions have the meanings hereby assigned to them: (a) Bars and rods 	Rolled, extruded, drawn or forged products, not in coils, which have a uniform solid cross section along their whole length in 	the shape of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), equilateral triangles or regular convex polygons (including "flattened 	circles" and "modified rectangles", of which two opposite sides are convex arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal 	length and parallel). Products with a rectangular (including square), triangular or polygonal cross section may have corners 	rounded along their whole length.The thickness of such products which have a rectangular (including "modified rectangular") 	cross section exceeds one-tenth of the width. The expression also covers cast or sintered products, of the same forms and 	dimensions, which have been subsequently worked after production (otherwise than by simple trimming or descaling), provided 	that they have not thereby assumed the character of articles or products of other headings. (b) Profiles 	Rolled, extruded, drawn, forged or formed products, coiled or not, of a uniform cross section along their whole length, which 	do not conform to any of the definitions of bars, rods, wire, plates, sheets, strip, foil, tubes or pipes. The expression also 	covers cast or sintered products, of the same forms, which have been subsequently worked after production (otherwise than 	by simple trimming or descaling), provided that they have not thereby assumed the character of articles or products of other 	headings. (c) Wire 	Rolled, extruded or drawn products, in coils, which have a uniform solid cross section along their whole length in the shape 	of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), equilateral triangles or regular convex polygons (including "flattened circles" 	and "modified rectangles", of which two opposite sides are convex arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal length 	and parallel). Products with a rectangular (including square), triangular or polygonal cross section may have corners rounded 	along their whole length. The thickness of such products which have a rectangular (including "modified rectangular") cross 	section exceeds one-tenth of the width. (d) Plates, sheets, strip and foil 	Flat-surfaced products (other than the unwrought products of heading 7901), coiled or not, of solid rectangular (other than 	square) cross section with or without rounded corners (including "modified rectangles" of which two opposite sides are convex 	arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal length and parallel) of a uniform thickness, which are: 		- of rectangular (including square) shape with a thickness not exceeding one-tenth of the width, 		- of a shape other than rectangular or square, of any size, provided that they do not assume the character of articles or 		products of other headings. 	Heading 7905 applies, inter alia, to plates, sheets, strip and foil with patterns (for example, grooves, ribs, checkers, tears, 	buttons, lozenges) and to such products which have been perforated, corrugated, polished or coated, provided that they do 	not thereby assume the character of articles or products of other headings. (e) Tubes and pipes 	Hollow products, coiled or not, which have a uniform cross section with only one enclosed void along their whole length in 	the shape of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), equilateral triangles or regular convex polygons, and which have 	a uniform wall thickness. Products with a rectangular (including square), equilateral triangular or regular convex polygonal 	cross section, which may have corners rounded along their whole length, are also to be considered as tubes and pipes 	provided the inner and outer cross sections are concentric and have the same form and orientation. Tubes and pipes of the 	foregoing cross sections may be polished, coated, bent, threaded, drilled, waisted, expanded, cone-shaped or fitted with 	flanges, collars or rings.  Subheading Note 1. In this chapter the following expressions have the meanings hereby assigned to them: (a) Zinc, not alloyed 	Metal containing by weight at least 97.5 percent of zinc. (b) Zinc alloys 	Metallic substances in which zinc predominates by weight over each of the other elements, provided that the total content 	by weight of such other elements exceeds 2.5 percent. (c) Zinc dust 	Dust obtained by condensation of zinc vapor, consisting of spherical particles which are finer than zinc powders. At least 80 	percent by weight of the particles pass through a sieve with 63 micrometers (microns) mesh. It must contain at least 85 	percent by weight of metallic zinc.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN80</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN80</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Note 1. In this chapter the following expressions have the meanings hereby assigned to them: (a) Bars and rods 	Rolled, extruded, drawn or forged products, not in coils, which have a uniform solid cross section along their whole length in 	the shape of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), equilateral triangles or regular convex polygons (including "flattened 	circles" and "modified rectangles", of which two opposite sides are convex arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal 	length and parallel). Products with a rectangular (including square), triangular or polygonal cross section may have corners 	rounded along their whole length.The thickness of such products which have a rectangular (including "modified rectangular") 	cross section exceeds one-tenth of the width. The expression also covers cast or sintered products, of the same forms and 	dimensions, which have been subsequently worked after production (otherwise than by simple trimming or descaling), provided 	that they have not thereby assumed the character of articles or products of other headings. (b) Profiles 	Rolled, extruded, drawn, forged or formed products, coiled or not, of a uniform cross section along their whole length, which 	do not conform to any of the definitions of bars, rods, wire, plates, sheets, strip, foil, tubes or pipes. The expression also 	covers cast or sintered products, of the same forms, which have been subsequently worked after production (otherwise than 	by simple trimming or descaling), provided that they have not thereby assumed the character of articles or products of other 	headings. (c) Wire 	Rolled, extruded or drawn products, in coils, which have a uniform solid cross section along their whole length in the shape 	of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), equilateral triangles or regular convex polygons (including "flattened circles" 	and "modified rectangles", of which two opposite sides are convex arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal length 	and parallel). Products with a rectangular (including square), triangular or polygonal cross section may have corners rounded 	along their whole length. The thickness of such products which have a rectangular (including "modified rectangular") cross 	section exceeds one-tenth of the width. (d) Plates, sheets, strip and foil 	Flat-surfaced products (other than the unwrought products of heading 8001), coiled or not, of solid rectangular (other than 	square) cross section with or without rounded corners (including "modified rectangles" of which two opposite sides are convex 	arcs, the other two sides being straight, of equal length and parallel) of a uniform thickness, which are: 		- of rectangular (including square) shape with a thickness not exceeding one-tenth of the width, 		- of a shape other than rectangular or square, of any size, provided that they do not assume the character of articles or 		products of other headings. (e) Tubes and pipes 	Hollow products, coiled or not, which have a uniform cross section with only one enclosed void along their whole length in 	the shape of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), equilateral triangles or regular convex polygons, and which have 	a uniform wall thickness. Products with a rectangular (including square), equilateral triangular or regular convex polygonal 	cross section, which may have corners rounded along their whole length, are also to be considered as tubes and pipes 	provided the inner and outer cross sections are concentric and have the same form and orientation. Tubes and pipes of the 	foregoing cross sections may be polished, coated, bent, threaded, drilled, waisted, expanded, cone-shaped or fitted with 	flanges, collars or rings.  Subheading Note 1. In this chapter the following expressions have the meanings hereby assigned to them: (a) Tin, not alloyed 	Metal containing by weight at least 99 percent of tin, provided that the content by weight of any bismuth or copper is less 	than the limit specified in the following table:  TABLE - Other elements _______________________________________________ Element			Limiting content % by weight Bi   Bismuth	0.1 Cu   Copper		0.4 _______________________________________________  (b) Tin alloys 	Metallic substances in which tin predominates by weight over each of the other elements, provided that: 	(i) The total content by weight of such other elements exceeds 1 percent; or 	(ii) The content by weight of either bismuth or copper is equal to or greater than the limit specified in the foregoing table.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN81</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN81</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Subheading Note 1. Note 1 to chapter 74, defining "bars and rods", "profiles", "wire", and "plates, sheets, strip and foil" applies, mutatis mutandis, to 	this chapter.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN82</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN82</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. Apart from blow torches and similar self-contained torches, portable forges, grinding wheels with frameworks, manicure or pedicure sets, and goods of heading 8209, this chapter covers only articles with a blade, working edge, working surface or other working part of: (a) Base metal; (b) Metal carbides or cermets; (c) Precious or semiprecious stones (natural, synthetic or reconstructed) on a support of base metal, metal carbide or cermet; 	or (d) Abrasive materials on a support of base metal, provided that the articles have cutting teeth, flutes, grooves or the like, of 	base metal, which retain their identity and function after the application of the abrasive. 2. Parts of base metal of the articles of this chapter are to be classified with the articles of which they are parts, except parts 	separately specified as such and toolholders for handtools (heading 8466). However, parts of general use as defined in note 2 	to section XV are in all cases excluded from this chapter. 	Heads, blades and cutting plates for electric shavers and electric hair clippers are to be classified in heading 8510. 3. Sets consisting of one or more knives of heading 8211 and at least an equal number of articles of heading 8215 are to be classified 	in heading 8215.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN83</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN83</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. For the purposes of this chapter, parts of base metal are to be classified with their parent articles. However, articles of iron or 	steel of heading 7312, 7315, 7317, 7318, or 7320, or similar articles of other base metal (chapters 74 to 76 and 78 to 81) are 	not to be taken as parts of articles of this chapter. 2. For the purposes of heading 8302, the word "castors" means those having a diameter (including, where appropriate, tires) not 	exceeding 75 mm, or those having a diameter (including, where appropriate, tires) exceeding 75 mm, provided that the width of 	the wheel or tire fitted thereto is less than 30 mm.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN84</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN84</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Millstones, grindstones or other articles of chapter 68; (b) Machinery or appliances (for example, pumps) of ceramic material and ceramic parts of machinery or appliances of any 	material (chapter 69); (c) Laboratory glassware (heading 7017); machinery, appliances or other articles for technical uses or parts thereof, of glass 	(heading 7019 or 7020); (d) Articles of heading 7321 or 7322 or similar articles of other base metals (chapters 74 to 76 or 78 to 81); (e) Vacuum cleaners of heading 8508; (f) Electromechanical domestic appliances of heading 8509; digital cameras of heading 8525; or (g) Hand-operated mechanical floor sweepers, not motorized (heading 9603). 2. Subject to the operation of Note 3 to Section XVI and subject to Note 9 to this chapter, a machine or appliance which answers 	to a description in one or more of the headings 8401 to 8424, or heading 8486 and at the same time to a description in one or 	more of the headings 8425 to 8480 is to be classified under the appropriate heading of the former group or under heading 8486, 	as the case may be, and not the latter group. Heading 8419 does not, however, cover: (a) Germination plant, incubators or brooders (heading 8436); (b) Grain-dampening machines (heading 8437); (c) Diffusing apparatus for sugar juice extraction (heading 8438); (d) Machinery for the heat treatment of textile yarns, fabrics or made up textile articles (heading 8451); or (e) Machinery or plant, designed for mechanical operation, in which a change of temperature, even if necessary, is subsidiary. Heading 8422 does not cover: (a) Sewing machines for closing bags or similar containers (heading 8452); or (b) Office machinery of heading 8472. Heading 8424 does not cover: (a) Ink-jet printing machines (heading 8443); (b) Water-jet cutting machines (heading 8456). 3. A machine tool for working any material which answers to a description in heading 8456 and at the same time to a description 	in heading 8457, 8458, 8459, 8460, 8461, 8464 or 8465 is to be classified in heading 8456. 	4. Heading 8457 applies only to machine tools for working metal, other than lathes (including turning centers), which can carry out 	different types of machining operations either: (a) by automatic tool change from a magazine or the like in conformity with a machining program (machining centers), (b) by the automatic use, simultaneously or sequentially, of different unit heads working on a fixed position workpiece (unit 	construction machines, single station), or (c) by the automatic transfer of the workpiece to different unit heads (multi-station transfer machines). 5.	(A) For the purposes of heading 8471, the expression "automatic data processing machines" means machines capable of : 		(i) Storing the processing program or programs and at least the data immediately necessary for the execution of the program; 		(ii) Being freely programmed in accordance with the requirements of the user; 		(iii) Performing arithmetical computations specified by the user; and 		(iv) Executing, without human intervention, a processing program which requires them to modify their execution, by logical 			decision during the processing run. 	(B) Automatic data processing machines may be in the form of systems consisting of a variable number of separate units. 	(C) Subject to paragraphs (D) and (E) below, a unit is to be regarded as being part of an automatic data processing system if it 		meets all of the following conditions : 		(i) It is of a kind solely or principally used in an automatic data processing system; 		(ii) It is connectable to the central processing unit either directly or through one or more other units; and 		(iii) It is able to accept or deliver data in a form (codes or signals) which can be used by the system. 		Separately presented units of an automatic data processing machine are to be classified in heading 8471. 		However, keyboards, X-Y co-ordinate input devices and disk storage units which satisfy the conditions of paragraphs (C) (ii) 		and (C) (iii) above, are in all cases to be classified as units of heading 8471. 	(D) Heading 8471 does not cover the following when presented separately, even if they meet all of the conditions set forth in 		Note 5 (C) above : 		(i) Printers, copying machines, facsimile machines, whether or not combined; 		(ii) Apparatus for the transmission or reception of voice, images or other data, including apparatus for communication in a 			wired or wireless network (such as a local or wide area network); 		(iii) Loudspeakers and microphones; 		(iv) Television cameras, digital cameras and video camera recorders; 		(v) Monitors and projectors, not incorporating television reception apparatus. 	(E) Machines incorporating or working in conjunction with an automatic data processing machine and performing a specific 		function other than data processing are to be classified in the headings appropriate to their respective functions or, failing 		that, in residual headings. 6. Heading 8482 applies, inter alia, to polished steel balls, the maximum and minimum diameters of which do not differ from the 	nominal diameter by more than 1 percent or by more than 0.05 mm, whichever is less. Other steel balls are to be classified under 	heading 7326. 7. A machine which is used for more than one purpose is, for the purposes of classification, to be treated as if its principal purpose 	were its sole purpose. 	Subject to note 2 to this chapter and note 3 to section XVI, a machine the principal purpose of which is not described in any 	heading or for which no one purpose is the principal purpose is, unless the context otherwise requires, to be classified in heading 	8479. Heading 8479 also covers machines for making rope or cable (for example, stranding, twisting or cabling machines) from 	metal wire, textile yarn or any other material or from a combination of such materials. 8. For the purposes of heading 8470, the term "pocket-size" applies only to machines the dimensions of which do not exceed 170 	mm x 100 mm x 45 mm. 9.	(A) Notes 8 (a) and 8 (b) to Chapter 85 also apply with respect to the expressions " semiconductor devices" and " electronic 		integrated circuits", respectively, as used in this Note and in heading 8486. However, for the purposes of this Note and of 		heading 8486, the expression " semiconductor devices" also covers photosensitive semiconductor devices and light emitting 		diodes. 	(B) For the purposes of this Note and of heading 8486, the expression "manufacture of flat panel displays" covers the fabrication 		of substrates into a flat panel. It does not cover the manufacture of glass or the assembly of printed circuit boards or other 		electronic components onto the flat panel. The expression "flat panel display" does not cover cathode-ray tube technology. 	(C) Heading 8486 also includes machines and apparatus solely or principally of a kind used for : 		(i) the manufacture or repair of masks and reticles; 		(ii) assembling semiconductor devices or electronic integrated circuits; 		(iii) lifting, handling, loading or unloading of boules, wafers, semiconductor devices, electronic integrated circuits and flat 		panel displays. 	(D) Subject to Note 1 to Section XVI and Note 1 to Chapter 84, machines and apparatus answering to the description in heading 		8486 are to be classified in that heading and in no other heading of the tariff schedule.  Subheading Notes 1. For the purposes of subheading 8471.49, the term "systems" means automatic data processing machines whose units satisfy 	the conditions laid down in note 5(C) to chapter 84 and which comprise at least a central processing unit, one in
put unit (for 	example, a keyboard or a scanner), and one output unit (for example, a visual display unit or a printer). 2. Subheading 8482.40 applies only to bearings with cylindrical rollers of a uniform diameter not exceeding 5 mm and having a 	length which is at least three times the diameter. The ends of the rollers may be rounded.</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN85</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN85</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Electrically warmed blankets, bed pads, foot-muffs or the like; electrically warmed clothing, footwear or ear pads or other 	electrically warmed articles worn on or about the person; (b) Articles of glass of heading 7011; (c) Machines and apparatus of heading 8486; (d) Vacuum apparatus of a kind used in medical, surgical, dental or veterinary sciences (heading 9018); or (e) Electrically heated furniture of chapter 94. 2. Headings 8501 to 8504 do not apply to goods described in heading 8511, 8512, 8540, 8541 or 8542. 	However, metal tank mercury arc rectifiers remain classified in heading 8504. 3. Heading 8509 covers only the following electromechanical machines of the kind commonly used for domestic purposes: (a) Floor polishers, food grinders and mixers, and fruit or vegetable juice extractors, of any weight; (b) Other machines provided the weight of such machines does not exceed 20 kg, exclusive of extra interchangeable parts or 	detachable auxiliary devices. 	The heading does not, however, apply to fans or ventilating or recycling hoods incorporating a fan, whether or not fitted with filters 	(heading 8414), centrifugal clothes dryers (heading 8421), dishwashing machines (heading 8422), household washing machines 	(heading 8450), roller or other ironing machines (heading 8420 or 8451), sewing machines (heading 8452), electric scissors 	(heading 8467) or to electrothermic appliances (heading 8516). 4. For the purposes of heading 8523 : (a) "Solid-state non-volatile storage devices "(for example,"flash memory cards" or "flash electronic storage cards") are storage 	devices with a connecting socket, comprising in the same housing one or more flash memories (for example, "FLASH 	E²PROM") in the form of integrated circuits mounted on a printed circuit board. They may include a controller in the form of 	an integrated circuit and discrete passive components, such as capacitors and resistors; (b) The term "smart cards" means cards which have embedded in them one or more electronic integrated circuits (a 	microprocessor, random access memory (RAM) or read-only memory (ROM)) in the form of chips.These cards may contain 	contacts, a magnetic stripe or an embedded antenna but do not contain any other active or passive circuit elements. 5. For the purposes of heading 8534 "printed circuits" are circuits obtained by forming on an insulating base, by any printing process 	(for example, embossing, plating-up, etching) or by the "film circuit" technique, conductor elements, contacts or other printed 	components (for example, inductances, resistors, capacitors) alone or interconnected according to a pre-established pattern, 	other than elements which can produce, rectify, modulate or amplify an electrical signal (for example, semiconductor elements). 	The term "printed circuits" does not cover circuits combined with elements other than those obtained during the printing process, 	nor does it cover individual, discrete resistors, capacitors or inductances. Printed circuits may, however, be fitted with non-printed 	connecting elements. 	Thin- or thick-film circuits comprising passive and active elements obtained during the same technological process are to be 	classified in heading 8542. 6. For the purpose of heading 8536, "connectors for optical fibres, optical fibre bundles or cables" means connectors that simply 	mechanically align optical fibres end to end in a digital line system. They perform no other function, such as the amplification, 	regeneration or modification of a signal. 7. Heading 8537 does not include cordless infrared devices for the remote control of television receivers or other electrical equipment 	(heading 8543). 8. For the purposes of headings 8541 and 8542: (a) "Diodes, transistors and similar semiconductor devices" are semiconductor devices the operation of which depends on 	variations in resistivity on the application of an electric field; (b) "Electronic integrated circuits" are: 	(i) Monolithic integrated circuits in which the circuit elements (diodes, transistors, resistors, capacitors, inductances, etc.) 		are created in the mass (essentially) and on the surface of a semiconductor or compound semiconductor material (for 		example, doped silicon, gallium arsenide, silicon germanium, iridium phosphide) and are inseparably associated; 	(ii) Hybrid integrated circuits in which passive elements (resistors, capacitors, inductances, etc.), obtained by thin- or 		thick-film technology, and active elements (diodes, transistors, monolithic integrated circuits, etc.), obtained by 		semiconductor technology, are combined to all intents and purposes indivisibly, by interconnections of interconnecting 		cables, on a single insulating substrate (glass, ceramic, etc.). These circuits may also include discrete components; 	(iii) Multichip integrated circuits consisting of two or more interconnected monolithic integrated circuits combined to all intents 		and purposes indivisibly, whether or not on one or more insulating substrates, with or without leadframes, but with no 		other active or passive circuit elements. 	For the classification of the articles defined in this note, headings 8541 and 8542 shall take precedence over any other heading 	in the Nomenclature, except in the case of heading 8523, which might cover them by reference to, in particular, their function. 9. For the purposes of heading 8548, "spent primary cells, spent primary batteries and spent electric storage batteries" are those 	which are neither usable as such because of breakage, cutting up, wear or other reasons, nor capable of being recharged.  Subheading Note 1. Subheading 8527.12 covers only cassette players with built-in amplifier, without built-in loudspeaker, capable of operating without 	an external source of electric power and the dimensions of which do not exceed 170 mm x 100 mm x 45 mm.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN86</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN86</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Railway or tramway sleepers (cross-ties) of wood or of concrete, or concrete guide-track sections for hovertrains (heading 	4406 or 6810); (b) Railway or tramway track construction material of iron or steel of heading 7302; or (c) Electrical signaling, safety or traffic control equipment of heading 8530. 2. Heading 8607 applies, inter alia, to: (a) Axles, wheels, wheel sets (running gear), metal tires, hoops and hubs and other parts of wheels; (b) Frames, underframes, truck assemblies; (c) Axle boxes; brake gear; (d) Buffers for rolling-stock; hooks and other coupling gear and corridor connections; (e) Coachwork. 3. Subject to the provisions of note 1 above, heading 8608 applies, inter alia, to: (a) Assembled track, turntables, platform buffers, loading gauges; (b) Semaphores, mechanical signal discs, level crossing control gear, signal and point controls, and other mechanical (including 	electro-mechanical) signaling, safety or traffic control equipment, whether or not fitted for electric lighting, for railways, 	tramways, roads, inland waterways, parking facilities, port installations or airfields.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN87</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN87</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover railway or tramway rolling stock designed solely for running on rails. 2. For the purposes of this chapter, "tractors" means vehicles constructed essentially for hauling or pushing another vehicle, 	appliance or load, whether or not they contain subsidiary provision for the transport, in connection with the main use of the tractor, 	of tools, seeds, fertilizers or other goods. 	Machines and working tools designed for fitting to tractors of heading 8701 as interchangeable equipment remain classified in 	their respective headings even if presented with the tractor, and whether or not mounted on it. 3. Motor chassis fitted with cabs fall in headings 8702 to 8704, and not in heading 8706. 4. Heading 8712 includes all children's bicycles. Other children's cycles fall in heading 9503.       Subheading Note      1. Subheading 8708.22.00 covers:      (a)  front windscreens (windshields), rear windows and other windows, framed; and      (b)  front windscreens (windshields), rear windows and other windows, whether or not framed, incorporating heating devices or other electrical or electronic devices, when suitable for use solely or principally with the motor vehicles of headings 8701 to 8705.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN88</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN88</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Subheading Note 1. For the purposes of subheadings 8802.11 to 8802.40, the expression "unladen weight" means the weight of the machine in 	normal flying order, excluding the weight of the crew and of fuel and equipment other than permanently fitted items of equipment.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN89</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN89</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Note 1. A hull, an unfinished or incomplete vessel, assembled, unassembled or disassembled, or a complete vessel unassembled or 	disassembled, is to be classified in heading 8906 if it does not have the essential character of a vessel of a particular kind.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN90</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN90</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Articles of a kind used in machines, appliances or for other technical uses, of vulcanized rubber other than hard rubber 	(heading 4016), of leather or of composition leather (heading 4205) or of textile material (heading 5911); (b) Supporting belts or other support articles of textile material, whose intended effect on the organ to be supported or held 	derives solely from their elasticity (for example, maternity belts, thoracic support bandages, abdominal support bandages, 	supports for joints or muscles) (section XI); (c) Refractory goods of heading 6903; ceramic wares for laboratory, chemical or other technical uses, of heading 6909; (d) Glass mirrors, not optically worked, of heading 7009, or mirrors of base metal or of precious metal, not being optical elements 	(heading 8306 or chapter 71); (e) Goods of heading 7007, 7008, 7011, 7014, 7015 or 7017; (f) Parts of general use, as defined in note 2 to section XV, of base metal (section XV) or similar goods of plastics (chapter 39); (g) Pumps incorporating measuring devices, of heading 8413; weight-operated counting or checking machinery, or separately 	entered weights for balances (heading 8423); lifting or handling machinery (headings 8425 to 8428); paper or paperboard 	cutting machines of all kinds (heading 8441); fittings for adjusting work or tools on machine tools, of heading 8466, including 	fittings with optical devices for reading the scale (for example, "optical" dividing heads) but not those which are in themselves 	essentially optical instruments (for example, alignment telescopes); calculating machines (heading 8470); valves or other 	appliances of heading 8481, machines and apparatus (including apparatus for the projection or drawing of circuit patterns 	on sensitized semiconductor materials) of heading 8486; (h) Searchlights or spotlights of a kind used for cycles or motor vehicles (heading 8512); portable electric lamps of heading 	8513; cinematographic sound recording, reproducing or re-recording apparatus (heading 8519); sound-heads (heading 	8522); television cameras, digital cameras and video camera recorders (heading 8525); radar apparatus, radio navigational 	aid apparatus and radio remote control apparatus (heading 8526); connectors for optical fibers, optical fiber bundles and 	cables (heading 8536); numerical control apparatus (heading 8537); sealed beam lamp units of heading 8539; optical fiber 	cables of heading 8544; (ij) Searchlights or spotlights of heading 9405; (k) Articles of chapter 95; (l) Capacity measures, which are to be classified according to their constituent material; or (m) Spools, reels or similar supports (which are to be classified according to their constituent material, for example, in heading 	3923 or section XV). 2. Subject to note 1 above, parts and accessories for machines, apparatus, instruments or articles of this chapter are to be classified 	according to the following rules: (a) Parts and accessories which are goods included in any of the headings of this chapter or of chapter 84, 85 or 91 (other than 	heading 8487, 8548 or 9033) are in all cases to be classified in their respective headings; (b) Other parts and accessories, if suitable for use solely or principally with a particular kind of machine, instrument or apparatus, 	or with a number of machines, instruments or apparatus of the same heading (including a machine, instrument or apparatus 	of heading 9010, 9013 or 9031) are to be classified with the machines, instruments or apparatus of that kind; (c) All other parts and accessories are to be classified in heading 9033. 3. The provisions of notes 3 and 4 to section XVI apply also to this chapter. 4. Heading 9005 does not apply to telescopic sights for fitting to arms, periscopic telescopes for fitting to submarines or tanks, or 	to telescopes for machines, appliances, instruments or apparatus of this chapter or section XVI; such telescopic sights and 	telescopes are to be classified in heading 9013. 5. Measuring or checking optical instruments, appliances or machines which, but for this note, could be classified both in heading 	9013 and in heading 9031 are to be classified in heading 9031. 6. For the purposes of heading 9021, the expression “orthopedic appliances” means appliances for: (a) Preventing or correcting bodily deformities; or (b) Supporting or holding parts of the body following an illness, operation or injury. 	Orthopedic appliances include footwear and special insoles designed to correct orthopedic conditions, provided that they are 	either (1) made to measure or (2) mass-produced, entered singly and not in pairs and designed to fit either foot equally. 7. Heading 9032 applies only to: (a) Instruments and apparatus for automatically controlling the flow, level, pressure or other variables of liquids or gases, or for 	automatically controlling temperature, whether or not their operation depends on an electrical phenomenon which varies 	according to the factor to be automatically controlled, which are designed to bring this factor to, and maintain it at, a desired 	value, stabilized against disturbances, by constantly or periodically measuring its actual value; and (b) Automatic regulators of electrical quantities, and instruments or apparatus for automatically controlling non-electrical quantities 	the operation of which depends on an electrical phenomenon varying according to the factor to be controlled, which are 	designed to bring this factor to, and maintain it at, a desired value, stabilized against disturbances, by constantly or periodically 	measuring its actual value.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN91</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN91</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Clock or watch glasses or weights (classified according to their constituent material); (b) Watch chains (heading 7113 or 7117, as the case may be); (c) Parts of general use defined in note 2 to section XV, of base metal (section XV), or similar goods of plastics (chapter 39) or 	of precious metal or metal clad with precious metal (generally heading 7115); clock or watch springs are, however, to be 	classified as clock or watch parts (heading 9114); (d) Bearing balls (heading 7326 or 8482, as the case may be); (e) Articles of heading 8412 constructed to work without an escapement; (f) Ball bearings (heading 8482); or (g) Articles of chapter 85, not yet assembled together or with other components into watch or clock movements or into articles 	suitable for use solely or principally as parts of such movements (chapter 85). 2. Heading 9101 covers only watches with case wholly of precious metal or of metal clad with precious metal, or of the same 	materials combined with natural or cultured pearls, or precious or semiprecious stones (natural, synthetic or reconstructed) of 	headings 7101 to 7104.Watches with case of base metal inlaid with precious metal fall in heading 9102. 3. For the purposes of this chapter, the expression "watch movements" means devices regulated by a balance wheel and hairspring, 	quartz crystal or any other system capable of determining intervals of time, with a display or a system to which a mechanical 	display can be incorporated. Such watch movements shall not exceed 12 mm in thickness and 50 mm in width, length or diameter. 4. Except as provided in note 1, movements and other parts suitable for use both in clocks or watches and in other articles (for 	example, precision instruments) are to be classified in this chapter.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN92</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN92</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Parts of general use, as defined in note 2 to section XV, of base metal (section XV), or similar goods of plastics (chapter 39); (b) Microphones, amplifiers, loudspeakers, headphones, switches, stroboscopes or other accessory instruments, apparatus or 	equipment of chapter 85 or 90, for use with but not incorporated in or housed in the same cabinet as instruments of this 	chapter; (c) Toy instruments or apparatus (heading 9503); (d) Brushes for cleaning musical instruments (heading 9603); or (e) Collectors' pieces or antiques (heading 9705 or 9706). 2. Bows and sticks and similar devices used in playing the musical instruments of heading 9202 or 9206 entered with such instruments 	in numbers normal thereto and clearly intended for use therewith, are to be classified in the same heading as the relative 	instruments. 	Cards, discs and rolls of heading 9209 entered with an instrument are to be treated as separate articles and not as forming a 	part of such instrument.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN93</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN93</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Goods of chapter 36 (for example, percussion caps, detonators, signaling flares); (b) Parts of general use, as defined in note 2 to section XV, of base metal (section XV), or similar goods of plastics (chapter 39); (c) Armored fighting vehicles (heading 8710); (d) Telescopic sights or other optical devices suitable for use with arms, unless mounted on a firearm or entered with the firearm 	on which they are designed to be mounted (chapter 90); (e) Bows, arrows, fencing foils or toys (chapter 95); or (f) Collectors' pieces or antiques (heading 9705 or 9706). 2. In heading 9306, the reference to "parts thereof" does not include radio or radar apparatus of heading 8526.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN94</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN94</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Pneumatic or water mattresses, pillows or cushions, of chapter 39, 40 or 63; (b) Mirrors designed for placing on the floor or ground (for example, cheval-glasses (swing-mirrors)) of heading 7009; (c) Articles of chapter 71; (d) Parts of general use as defined in note 2 to section XV, of base metal (section XV), or similar goods of plastics (chapter 39), 	or safes of heading 8303; (e) Furniture specially designed as parts of refrigerating or freezing equipment of heading 8418; furniture specially designed for 	sewing machines (heading 8452); (f) Lamps or lighting fittings of chapter 85; (g) Furniture specially designed as parts of apparatus of heading 8518 (heading 8518), of heading 8519 or 8521 (heading 8522) 	or of headings 8525 to 8528 (heading 8529); (h) Articles of heading 8714; (ij) Dentists' chairs incorporating dental appliances of heading 9018 or dentists' spittoons (heading 9018); (k) Articles of chapter 91 (for example, clocks and clock cases); or (l) Toy furniture or toy lamps or lighting fittings (heading 9503), billiard tables or other furniture specially constructed for games 	(heading 9504), furniture for magic tricks or decorations (other than electric garlands) such as Chinese lanterns (heading 	9505). 2. The articles (other than parts) referred to in headings 9401 to 9403 are to be classified in those headings only if they are designed 	for placing on the floor or ground. 	The following are, however, to be classified in the above-mentioned headings even if they are designed to be hung, to be fixed 	to the wall or to stand one on the other: (a) Cupboards, bookcases, other shelved furniture (including single shelves presented with supports for fixing them to the wall) 	and unit furniture; (b) Seats and beds. 3. (a) In headings 9401 to 9403 references to parts of goods do not include references to sheets or slabs (whether or not cut to 	shape but not combined with other parts) of glass (including mirrors), marble or other stone or of any other material referred 	to in chapter 68 or 69. (b) Goods described in heading 9404, entered separately, are not to be classified in heading 9401, 9402 or 9403 as parts of 	goods. 4. For the purposes of heading 9406, the expression "prefabricated buildings" means buildings which are finished in the factory or 	put up as elements, entered together, to be assembled on site, such as housing or worksite accommodation, offices, schools, 	shops, sheds, garages or similar buildings.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN95</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN95</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Candles (heading 3406); (b) Fireworks or other pyrotechnic articles of heading 3604; (c) Yarns, monofilament, cords or gut or the like for fishing, cut to length but not made up into fishing lines, of chapter 39, heading 	4206 or section XI; (d) Sports bags or other containers of heading 4202, 4303 or 4304; (e) Sports clothing or fancy dress, of textiles, of chapter 61 or 62; (f) Textile flags or bunting, or sails for boats, sailboards or land craft, of chapter 63; (g) Sports footwear (other than skating boots with ice or roller skates attached) of chapter 64, or sports headgear of chapter 65; (h) Walking-sticks, whips, riding-crops or the like (heading 6602), or parts thereof (heading 6603); (ij) Unmounted glass eyes for dolls or other toys, of heading 7018; (k) Parts of general use, as defined in note 2 to section XV, of base metal (section XV), or similar goods of plastics (chapter 39); (l) Bells, gongs or the like of heading 8306; (m) Pumps for liquids (heading 8413), filtering or purifying machinery and apparatus for liquids or gases (heading 8421), electric 	motors (heading 8501), electric transformers (heading 8504), discs, tapes, solid-state non-volatile storage devices, "smart 	cards" and other media for the recording of sound or of other phenomena, whether or not recorded (heading 8523), radio 	remote control apparatus (heading 8526) or cordless infrared remote control devices (heading 8543); (n) Sports vehicles (other than sleds, bobsleds, toboggans and the like) of section XVII; (o) Children's bicycles (heading 8712); (p) Sports craft such as canoes and skiffs (chapter 89), or their means of propulsion (chapter 44 for such articles made of wood); (q) Spectacles, goggles or the like, for sports or outdoor games (heading 9004); (r) Decoy calls or whistles (heading 9208); (s) Arms or other articles of chapter 93; (t) Electric garlands of all kinds (heading 9405); (u) Racket strings, tents or other camping goods, or gloves, mittens and mitts (classified according to their constituent material); 	or (v) Tableware, kitchenware, toilet articles, carpets and other textile floor coverings, apparel, bed linen, table linen, toilet linen, 	kitchen linen and similar articles having a utilitarian function (classified according to their constituent material). 1/ 2. This chapter includes articles in which natural or cultured pearls, precious or semiprecious stones (natural, synthetic or 	reconstructed), precious metal or metal clad with precious metal constitute only minor constituents. 3. Subject to note 1 above, parts and accessories which are suitable for use solely or principally with articles of this chapter are to 	be classified with those articles. 4. Subject to the provisions of Note 1 above, heading 9503 applies, inter alia, to articles of this heading combined with one or more 	items, which cannot be considered as sets under the terms of General Interpretative Rule 3(b), and which, if presented separately, 	would be classified in other headings, provided the articles are put up together for retail sale and the combinations have the 	essential character of toys. 5. Heading 9503 does not cover articles which, on account of their design, shape or constituent material, are identifiable as intended 	exclusively for animals, for example, "pet toys" (classification in their own appropriate heading).  Subheading Note 1. Subheading 9504.50 covers: (a) Video game consoles from which the image is reproduced on a television receiver, a monitor or other external screen or 	surface; or (b) Video game machines having a self-contained video screen, whether or not portable. 	This subheading does not cover video game consoles or machines operated by coins, banknotes, bank cards, tokens or by any 	other means of payment (subheading 9504.30).
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN96</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN96</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Pencils for cosmetic or toilet uses (chapter 33); (b) Articles of chapter 66 (for example, parts of umbrellas or walking-sticks); (c) Imitation jewelry (heading 7117); (d) Parts of general use, as defined in note 2 to section XV, of base metal (section XV) or similar goods of plastics (chapter 39); (e) Cutlery or other articles of chapter 82 with handles or other parts of carving or molding materials; heading 9601 or 9602 	applies, however, to separately entered handles or other parts of such articles; (f) Articles of chapter 90 (for example, spectacle frames (heading 9003), mathematical drawing pens (heading 9017), brushes 	of a kind specialized for use in dentistry or for medical, surgical or veterinary purposes (heading 9018)); (g) Articles of chapter 91 (for example, clock or watch cases); (h) Musical instruments or parts or accessories thereof (chapter 92); (ij) Articles of chapter 93 (arms and parts thereof); (k) Articles of chapter 94 (for example, furniture, lamps and lighting fittings); (l) Articles of chapter 95 (toys, games, sports equipment); or (m) Works of art, collectors' pieces or antiques (chapter 97). 2. In heading 9602 the expression "vegetable or mineral carving material" means: (a) Hard seeds, pips, hulls and nuts and similar vegetable materials of a kind used for carving (for example, corozo and dom); (b) Amber, meerschaum, agglomerated amber and agglomerated meerschaum, jet and mineral substitutes for jet. 3. In heading 9603 the expression "prepared knots and tufts for broom or brush making" applies only to unmounted knots and tufts 	of animal hair, vegetable fiber or other material, which are ready for incorporation without division in brooms or brushes, or which 	require only such further minor processes as trimming to shape at the top, to render them ready for such incorporation. 4. Articles of this chapter, other than those of headings 9601 to 9606 or 9615, remain classified in the chapter whether or not 	composed wholly or partly of precious metal or metal clad with precious metal, of natural or cultured pearls, or precious or 	semiprecious stones (natural, synthetic or reconstructed). However, headings 9601 to 9606 and 9615 include articles in which 	natural or cultured pearls, precious or semiprecious stones (natural, synthetic or reconstructed), precious metal or metal clad 	with precious metal constitute only minor constituents.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
<texts>
<qualifier>hint</qualifier>
<text_element_id>HTS_FN97</text_element_id>
<reference_id>HTS_FN97</reference_id>
<deletion>false</deletion>
<validity_begin>1996-01-01</validity_begin>
<validity_end>9999-12-30</validity_end>
<text_element>
<language>EN</language>
<text>Notes 1. This chapter does not cover: (a) Unused postage or revenue stamps, postal stationery (stamped paper) or the like, of heading 4907; (b) Theatrical scenery, studio backdrops or the like, of painted canvas (heading 5907) except if they may be classified in heading 	9706; or (c) Pearls, natural or cultured, or precious or semiprecious stones (headings 7101 to 7103). 2. For the purposes of heading 9702, the expression "original engravings, prints and lithographs" means impressions produced 	directly, in black and white or in color, of one or of several plates wholly executed by hand by the artist, irrespective of the process 	or of the material employed by him, but not including any mechanical or photomechanical process. 3. Heading 9703 does not apply to mass-produced reproductions or works of conventional craftsmanship of a commercial character, 	even if these articles are designed or created by artists. 4. (a) Subject to notes 1 through 3 above, articles of this chapter are to be classified in this chapter and not in any other chapter 	of the tariff schedule. (b) Heading 9706 does not apply to articles of the preceding headings of this chapter. 5. Frames around paintings, drawings, pastels, collages or similar decorative plaques, engravings, prints or lithographs are to be 	classified with those articles, provided they are of a kind and of a value normal to those articles. Frames which are not of a kind 	or of avalue normal to the articles referred to in this note are to be classified separately.
</text>
</text_element>
</texts>
</body>
</legal_numbering_exchange>
